And we're not going to let anything stop
the traditions from happening at a
moment in time when our community needs
to continue to come together and
celebrate authentically who we are.
I am Mexican American so I take a lot
of pride in my culture and um I actually
moved out to Los Angeles and I'm away
from my family so it just connects me
more to my family.  Um spent in Mexico
before and so
it
lost the lives they gave us.  Homeland and
freedom.
Viva.
Long live Hidalgo.
Viva Bonds.
Viva.
Vivaende
viva.
Long live Mazolo.
Viva.
Long live Jiménez.
Long live Josefa Ortiz de Domínguez.  Long live
Vicente Guerrero!
Long
live Mexico!
Viva.
Long live Mexico.
The national anthem while standing at attention.
I think it's really beautiful eventually
in the time right now.  Um I know that a
lot of people were scared to come but I
wanted to show that you know I can be
here and represent the people who may
not have the ability to have come.  And
so yeah, I'm really glad that I was able
to show up and that they had such a
beautiful music, such beautiful food and
the people really amazing to see
everyone especially connected with the
rope.  Uh that was a very beautiful
element and uh yeah, everybody was
really friendly.  I really like that they
put on this event for us.  Long live
Mexico, long
live Mexico, long
live
Los Angeles is home.
Negrit ceremony has been here
city hall for decades.
Los Angeles, people los Angeles the
significance is that we are all bound by
our willingness and our demand for
freedom and independence and whether
you're Mexican American,
AfricanAmerican, Angloamerican,
AsianAmerican, all of our people have
had struggles against oppression and
struggles uh to take away our freedoms
and our people fight back against those
and we declare our independence.  Mexican
independence day is a reminder that
those of us who believe in justice,
those of us who believe in freedom,
those of us who believe in equality, if
we fight even when it's darkest, like
it's dark today, we will win and we will
be victorious.
events like this just really underscore
the the opportunity to come together and
the importance of coming together as a
community and while it may be affecting
uh uh Mexicans today uh tomorrow may be
another ethnic group tomorrow another
group after that.  So we know we have to
work together otherwise we're going to
all fall.  It's important that we talk
about our freedom, talk about what we
have in common.  I talk about our ability
to work together.  And so for me
represents that.
I think that's wonderful because I
really like those colors.  like the
energy here so positive and so like even
despite from another country I don't
speak Spanish but I feel so like at home
like I think definitely was speaking
Spanish in my previous lives because I
feel so good I feel like I'm belong here
so thank you for this uh like I don't
know all the organizers and all the
people who made this possible I feels
very nice to be here I just was walking
around I hear some music I thought I
have to check it so here I
Happy Mexican Independence
peace, love and all the best things and
positive vibes.
You know today for the city of Los
Angeles I think it's so fitting that one
of our toughest Mexican Americans on the
councilis Hernández is running this year
a year where there's so much fear so
much uncertainty but today was supposed
to be a day of celebration a day of
happiness and we're making that happen
the diversity of our city is seen and
the folks that are here and I'm just
happy to be a part of it to be able to
talk about the importance of the Mexican
American community and its impact in Los
Angeles internationally, locally,  at all
levels, Mexican Americans have always
shown to be good Americans and by
continuing to celebrate our culture,
that's our way of fighting.
We should keep fighting for ours because
we built we made a difference in Los
Angeles.
Mexican independence day, but I think we
shouldn't see it as
we independence transcends
any
supposed to be something we can all
recognize.
should be celebrating any independence
from tyranny and I think that's why so
many people have come out to support
because we recognize that.
I want to remind our community that
there is strengthening numbers and there
are uh so many of us here in Los Angeles
and where government isn't able to
intervene or support.  We have wonderful
partnerships with the council generals
from all the different Latin American
countries, from our non-profit
organizations, from our labor unions.
This is what they're trying to erase and
stop us from doing.  They're trying to
prevent us from being authentically who
we are.  And this event with everyone
that's turned out is a reflection that
we are in fact here and we will stay
here.
Right now, one of the most powerful
things we could do to protect our
families here in Los Angeles is to build
community.  It's to know who your
neighbor is.  It's to have their phone
number and call and you can call them in
case of an emergency.  Events like these
are what help build relationships with
community so that we can survive these
tough moments.  And that's what helps the
government do the right thing.  That's
what overcomes these moments is
community power, people power.
Hello everyone.  I'm Natalia Bow and
here's what's happening in LA this week.
Keeping the lights on, Boil Heights has
suffered with almost 2000 street lights
out across the community.  Council member
Isabel Hurada has identified a million
for a dedicated street crew to ensure
that the streetlights come back on and
stay on.
I live literally a block away.  I could
walk here and I run this route uh maybe
four times to five times a week.  I could
tell you I run it at night and it's very
very dark.  I have my flashlight that I
take with me so I know it's not safe.
When I came into office, we heard from
Eagle Rock to Highland Park to Bo to
downtown LA.  People don't feel safe and
part of that is because all the lights
are out.
In Heights alone, 900
streetlights are out and that's the
highest number in the city.  And so in
October of this year, we allocated $.07
million to make sure that we have a
dedicated street crew to make sure that
the lighting is going to stay on.
We have scientific data that proves what
community members feel intrinsically
that brighter lights, adequate lighting
actually reduces crime.  I haven't seen
the lights on on this streep maybe in
about four years now.
I feel like we've been making this known
for years and nobody's listening.  You know,
we just get the shrug off.
Communities like Boil Heights deserve to
have their lights on.  Public safety
starts with equitable city service
delivery.  We are a community that is
often overlooked in favor of other
districts in the area.
Speak up, being loud.  We have to make
our voices heard in order for government
to move, in order for our
representatives to know what uh is most
important to us.
The work can get done.
I'm excited to see what this is going to
look like at nighttime now with the
lights on.  Let's work and keep the
lights on.
In P Union, the shovels are poised and
crews are ready to improve accessibility
in the neighborhood.  The project is tied
to affordable housing.  So living,
working, walking, and accessing Pik
Union is set to be better than ever.
Today we are doing the ground breaking
for a significant amount of street
infrastructure being invested here in
Pico Union.
We are doing crossws.  We are doing ADA
accessibility ramps, sidewalks.  We're
doing the street lights.
This is a phenomenal day for PE Union.
When we talk about the future of
infrastructure investment in the city of
Los Angeles, this project exemplifies
and embodies the future, especially
where affordable housing is our
centerpiece.  So this project is tied to
an affordable housing development that
has moved forward in this area.
Recognizing that we are bringing more
people to this area, we wanted to make
sure that people could have safe street
infrastructure so that kids can walk to
the school safely, parents can walk to
work safely and everyone can come back
home.  We really believe that our streets
should be designed for people and you do
that by making sure that people feel
safe walking in their neighborhoods.  And so
that's really our motivation.  We as a
city are coming through for our
community members, for the voters, for
the taxpayers.  I'm just glad that we're
able to that and have this day today
for them.  And with that, we're going to
grab our shovels and we're going to
break some ground.
Let's go infrastructure.
Council woman Heather Hut, her office,
and local volunteers gather to help with
food supplies for the holidays.  But much
needed food gaveaway helped neighbors in
need, allowing everyone to celebrate.
We're at Michelle and Barack Obama
Sports Complex right here on Obama
Boulevard.  And what we're doing is a
much needed food giveaway.  We have fresh
vegetables, as maybe you can see in the
background.  We have turkey and we have a
line that started really early this
morning because people are on the knee.
We're giving to the community.  we're
giving just for people who are just
might be a little bit less fortunate
when it comes to Christmas and food and
making sure you know the community just
has something to eat with their family
helping people and giving back it's the
holiday season and times are hard
been here for like every four years and I
come back just to help and give back
this impacts a lot of people and she's
impacting the community different
communities as Well, just seeing the
smiles on these people faces and seeing how
grateful they are.  It is an amazing
thing.  The volunteers are from the
community.  Many of them are my family
members.  Everybody's here to give up a
hand.  My whole team has been out here
since early this morning
organizing.
Food is really expensive and people have
food insecurities.
This should stabilize how they feel
about what their next meal is.  And that's what
we're trying to satisfy.
Two sides of the same coin are at work
in South LA with funding for green and
sustainable projects.  Parks in the area
getting EV chargers and more tree
coverage.  Both of which will help bring
down pollution levels in the
neighborhoods.
We Harbor Park in South Alb
facilities of the South Ecola for the
EV Chargers.
This is part of a bigger program,
universal basic mobility which is a 30
million investment in South Los Angeles
to bring mobility options, access to
opportunity and increase transportation
equity while reducing greenhouse gas
emissions at the same time.
The bureau guns uh invited to
participate in the TCC grant program and
our role is to install 16 EV chargers
across four different parks here in
South LA.  Our charging program is a
little different than most.  Um, we
installed chargers on existing
infrastructure.  Uh, we found that our
existing streetlight circuits had extra
capacity when we converted to LEDs.  We
currently have over 800 chargers
throughout the city of Los Angeles.
So these chargers are going to offer a
convenient place for people to charge
close to home, especially for people who
may have challenges charging at home,
like people who live in multi-family
housing.
So I we're working with community
organizations such as three people to
increase the community canopy in South
Alm
canopy expansion project and its main
goal is to advance shade and tree equity
by planting 4,000 trees and city
parkways and also distributing 2,000
fruit or shade trees to residents to
plant in their home.
Both projects will help each other.  The
charging station will help uh with
pollution with less uh carbon monoxide
and in and the area and uh the tree
planning will help absorb that uh carbon
monoxide with the events that we had in
certain parks where we gave away free
seeds and like he said with the trees we
were also teaching you how to plant and
provide and take care of the tree.
This is the first park that we're
completing the installations.  Uh we are
working uh in different parks in South
where we are also installing EV
chargers.  Our next park will be Bermont
Square, South Park and the wetlands.
LA sanitation takes in hazardous
household waste at its safe centers.  The
LAWP is hosting a customer service
Saturday on January 17th and volunteer
signups are open for the 2026 Greater
Los Angeles homeless count.  The stories
up next on City Beat.
LA Sanitation wants to let Angelinos
know that its safe centers are permanent
collection sites for hazardous household
and electronic waste.  Safe stands for
solvents, automotive, flammables, and
electronics.  And the safe centers take
in items such as aerosol cans,
batteries, paints, and more.  La City
Sanitation advises keeping items in
their original containers if possible
and placing waste securely in the trunk
separate from personal belongings.
Residents are allowed 15 gallons or up
to 125 lb per vehicle per visit to the
center.  For more information, visit Safe
Center under new battery collection
centers at the website
sanitation.lacity.gov.
The Los Angeles Department of Water and
Power invites Angelenos who need help
signing up for utility financial
assistance to attend customer support
Saturday.  Department of water and power
customer service centers at Kenshaw,
North Hills, and Wats will assist
residents with their programs.  The
one-on-one consultations will provide
ways to save water, power, and money
along with same day enrollment in
payment programs.
Angelinos will need to bring a valid ID,
proof of income, proof of disability if
applicable, and their LAWP bill, gas
bill, and phone bill.  No RSVP is needed
and bilingual representatives will be
available at customer support Saturday
on January 17th from 9 a.m.  to 2 p.m.
For more information, visit ladwp.com.
The Los Angeles Homeless Services
Authority, Laa has opened volunteer
registration for the 2026 Greater Los
Angeles Homeless Count.  Each January,
Losa's staff and volunteers count
unhoused Angelinos.  makeshift shelters,
tents, and vehicles.  According to LASA,
the 2026 Greater Los Angeles Homeless
Count will feature improvements in
staffing support, and the training
materials have been simplified to ensure
consistency across all LA regions.  La is
seeking to recruit 6,500 volunteers to
assist with the homeless count, which is
taking place this year on January 20th,
21st, and 22. For more information or to
register as a volunteer, go to
count.la.org.
Council woman Heather Hut reviewed 2025.
With improvements on key issues in her
ongoing district, Hut's 2026
resolutions are for more progress in
housing, continued expansion of parks,
and keeping the economy strong.
I'm Council Woman Heatherhood of the
10th district, city of Los Angeles.  I am
proud of the work that we've been able
to do.  I'm proud of government and
community working together.
Since I got here in 2022, we've really been
working on homelessness.  And I'm
proud to say we've successfully bought
down homelessness in our district by 29%
and we've gotten over 2,000 people in
permanent housing.  I'm really proud of
that.  And you know, it's not over.
There's more work to be done.
I'm committed to using every city
resource to bring more parks into CD.
We're currently working on a plan to do
a major expansion to Soul International
Park.  In the past few months, we've
secured major renovations to be done to
Chatu Park and Laat Park.  We also just
finished renovating the football field
here at Obama Sports Complex.  So when we
think of Korea town, it's a very dense
population and in going outside the box
thinking of ways to make usable spaces
is why we expanded PO Peel library to
make a library part and we should see
the completion of that real soon.  With
the World Cup, Allstar Weekend, Super
Bowl and the Olympics all heading to Los
Angeles, we're standing on the edge of a
massive economic boom.  But a boom only
matters if the wealth stays in the
neighborhood.  This is why our office
launched our small business workshop
series by giving our local businesses
access to tools like RAM.  They can
position themselves to secure formal
city contracts, transforming them from
spectators into vendors and workers that
will make these games possible.
We're going to celebrate
all the words of Martin Luther King.  We
have the Mok parade coming in January.
I'm excited.  It's running all through
the 10th district.  So, come out to King
Boulevard and see all of the joy that
comes with the civil rights fight.  And
then Love Hut.  It is something I do in
women's months to remind women about how
important they are and to know that I
care about their struggle.
I can't believe we're almost at 26.
Continuing to get our unhoused neighbors
the housing and resources they need.
That's number one.  Every single day
continues growing park space across the
district.  There's so many children and
families who have limited access to
being outside to being parks and
district and I feel like they're in
necessity.  So I'm committing to making
sure we balance the gap.
I feel like we had some lessons learned
in 25. 25 showed how resilient Los
Angeles is.  And then we'll move on with
that strength and resilience in 26.
All the good boy and girl dogs at the LA
Animal Services shelters got holiday
treats and toys.  While the generous
gifts are a help, the intention is to
highlight the dogs and help get them
into their forever homes.
Today, the Karen Cooper Foundation
brought Santaximal
Services centers.
We're actually bringing Christmas toys
to the shelter here.  Actually, there's
1100 toys that we're bringing.  Really
wonderful toys and treats for all the
shelter dogs that are here.  What else
can I say?  Christmas came early for the
shelter fets in LA City.
We know these shelter dogs don't really
have that much of an opportunity to have
any joy during the holidays.  So what we
do is we bring them all these treats.
The other reason that we do it is to
draw attention to the adoptions that are
so much needed.
Any animal that you know goes to a home,
it's still important for us because it
makes a lot needed space in the shelters.
We wanted to adopt a dog.  So he just
came and he fell in love one of the
dogs and I was at work when he told me
he already adopted him and I was like
why don't you tell me when then when I
came to visit him I'm like my heart
melted too.  So I'm like so happy that I
decided to get this dog.
Super happy right now.
I know we are both super happy right
now.  That's all I can say.
Michelle and I are here for this cause.
We're here to bring Christmas to them.
But at the end of the day, what needs to
really happen is these little guys and
gals need to be in their forever homes.
It's really helpful to adopt a dog that
would change a life.
To find more ways to support the
department, whether it's volunteering,
adopting, or donating, you can visit
laanimalservices.com.
The recent LA Reigns couldn't dent the
community spirit on display at the
annual kanza festival.  In fact, legend
has it that rain on this parade is a
sign of good luck and blessings to come.
The question came up, what are we going to
do foranza?
Why don't we have a parade?
What the Kan does is it brings in the
new year.  The theme of this year's
lair is
which is literally resurrection.  And so
we're in a resurrection period.
I mean to me is celebrating Black Pride.
So just to have this moment for us to be
able to gather together and do something
meaningful with no drama, fun times.  LT
Park is always a good time.  I'm excited
to be out here getting these ladies.  39
and over.  We get out here double dunch
line dance hul play games encourage
each other.  Just bringing back childhood
nostalgia.
We get excited
about all the fun, the car and the
margin and the walking and all the good
things that are in this community.
Just glad to be here and brave at 77
to be able to hang with the young folks.
When you walk in the rain at time, you
got blessings.  That's the things you
remember.  The more rain, the greater the
blessings.   The
LA Civil Rights Department is firmly
focused on ensuring that hate has no
home in LA.  Executive director Capr Mck
spoke about the department's year of
action, campaigning for civil rights and
civil society and a Los Angeles that
lights the way for all.
has no home in Los Angeles.
The relaunch of the campaign called Just
Say Hello sends a strong message that
hate has no home in Los Angeles.  We want
to build a sense of community, a
welcoming feeling with Angelino's.
So our reparations report is about 400
pages of the African-American experience
in Los Angeles over a 100year period.
There are so many spaces where your
color speaks before you do in America
but even in the city of angels.  And so
we want to be intentional to send a
strong message that we cannot unsee some
of the harms of the past, some of the
traumas and to think about how we can as
a city write those wrongs.
We want to be a city where people can
live their best lives regardless of how
they identify.  We stand with folks while
they're going through their transition,
while they're looking for jobs.  And so
when you think about uh the LGBTQ plus
community being discriminated in the
workplace, particularly the transgender
population, we want to make sure we have
a pathway for people to be
self-sustaining in Los Angeles.
Making sure that we have housing as well
as job fairs uh for this targeted
population is a just service.
I just want to say I love AAPI Month.
Asian-American Pacific Islander Month is
one of my favorite months in the city.  I
love the celebration, the food, the
colors, the community, the pride.  Of
course, we had a number of elected
officials, including our very own John
Lee, Nept Raman, many others.  That's
what I really love about our elected
officials is you may represent a group
in your identity, but you go out and you
celebrate all of Los Angeles every
heritage month.
We call our service day Tom Lebong day
of service.  Tom Lebong loved people.
Oftentimes bringing together people from
different backgrounds.  Um and the
opportunity for us to do Tom Lebon's day
of service gave us a moment for people
to work shoulder to shoulder um with
their fellow Angelinos and have that
common connection of wanting to serve.
We need to understand that it takes all
of us to build a better Los Angeles.
We are intentional here at LA Civil
Rights to say, "Regardless of your
faith, we stand with you. We don't have
Kate crime stopping at the door just
based on your skin color or how you
identify. We also have tremendous hate
crimes happening against folks based on
their faith. So we want to be unified
with uh all faiths to say we see you. We
stand with you. We celebrate you and we
want to create a Los Angeles where
people are freaked to worship as they
wish and to not feel like they're at
risk if  they're going to temple or going
to the mosk or going to their churches.
We've been able to support uh folks with
know your rights information with
Angelinos. We even had to know your
rights fair at my beloved Calst LA where
we had 19 service organizations to
provide advice, guidance, resources for students
at the Cter Lake campus during
one of the toughest times of the ice
raids in the city of angels.
message to our immigrants that you
belong  here.  And so the campaign is I
belong, you belong, we belong.
You know, people often say, and hey, go back
to where you belong.  We wanted to
blanket the city with a message that
everyone belongs.
We were intentional to do this in a
number of languages.  But our first
language out of the box, we did it in
Spanish.
Many of us have come from different
places and spaces for the freedom and
the liberties Los Angeles offers us all.
Our city is strong.  We are standing with
all communities.  I want you to know we
have your back.  We are here for you and
we are building Los Angeles for all.
In this week's things to do, help keep
MLK Jr. Dream alive at Freedom Festival.
Enjoy a guided tightful walk at Cabrio,
and get those Legos clicking at a brick
play date in Korea Toown.  All this up
next on things to do.
It's Freedom Festival happening on MLK
day Monday, January 19th.  Join Council
President Marqueis Harris Dawson,
council member Price and Council woman
Heather Hut in partnership with
community coalition and destination
Kenshaw to celebrate the life and legacy
of Martin  Luther King Jr. According to
council president Harris Dawson, this
yearly staple provides hundreds of South
LA residents with resources, culture,
and connection.  This year's festival
highlights the impact and unity in
action with the theme still we rise
keeping the dream alive.  Head to Lamert
Park for a freedom festival on the
Martin Luther King Jr. Holiday Monday,
January 19th from 11 a.m.  until 5 p.m.
For more information, visit the
Instagram account of Council President
Marque Harison at MHDCD8.
Enjoy a guided tide pool walk with the
Cabrio Marine Aquarium Educators on
Saturday, January 17th as they interpret
the various habitats of the Cabrio Beach
Coastal Park.  The walk begins at the
aquarium courtyard and takes in the
native gardens, salt marsh, beaches, and
tide pools.  Along the way, you'll see
fossils, native plants, birds, and other
interesting finds.
Head outside, bring a snack, and meet at
the aquarium for a tide pool walk on
Saturday, January 17th at 1:30 p.m.  For
more information, see the  events
calendar at cabriomarineaquarium.org.
Join the Los Angeles Public Library for
brick play date at the PO Pico Koreaown
branch library on January 17th.  If you
love to build things, join the playdate
at the library.  Families are welcome to
come and use their imagination to build
and play with the Legos libraries.  This
activity is recommended for kids ages
four and up.  Head to the community room
at the Pico Korea Town Branch Library
for the hands-on activity.  Brick play
date on Saturday, January 17th at 1:30
p.m.  For more information, visit
lapl.orgevents.
And that's a look at some things to do.
And that's all for this week.  I'm
Natalia Bob and from all of us here at
LA this week, thank you so much for
joining us.  Remember that you can watch
us online anytime at lascityview.org and
we're also on Instagram, Facebook, X,
and YouTube.  See you next time for more
LA this week.
Good morning, welcome to the
Los Angeles City Council.  Today is
Friday, the ninth day
of  January,
my dear
Co-President Harris Dawsen's birthday.
Public comment would be accepted in person today.
We continue with the
roll call. Bloomfield, Harris Dawsen,
Hernandez, Jurado Le Marian, Padilla, Park,
Price, Romen, Rodriguez, Soto
Martinez, Yoslovlski, 14 members
present and a quorum. Mr. President,
very good. First item of business.
Approval of the minutes of
December 12, 2025. Councilor Rodriguez
approves. Moskera, what else?
Commanding resolutions to be approved.
Councilor Park, second.
Today is Friday, but I believe
the Pledge of Allegiance is due.
We have a volunteer, Councilor Park,
please stand and if you can, place
your right hand over your heart.
Begin. I do pledge allegiance to the flag of
the United States of America in the
Republic, which stands for one nation
under God, indivisible, with liberty and
justice for all.
Very good, Madam Secretary. What  What else is
there?
But I know I'm familiar with the pledge
of allegiance to the flag. May I go through
the agenda? Yes. Well, items 1 through 8
for which a public hearing has been held
. 9 through 31, no public hearing.
Ten votes are required for
consideration. Well, those items are
before us. No objections. We have
specials for this
morning's meeting. Members to my left, it looks
like Mr. Mcosker. Very well,
thank you very much, Mr. President.
I would like to call item number two special
for an amendment that's already being
circulated.
Well,
Councilor Jurado, you're standing
for a special. Yes, Mr. President.
23 and 24 for a separate vote.
Councilor Hernandez. Yes. Good morning,
President of the Council. May I call
items 23, 24, and 30 for comments and
continue item number 28 for one month?
We have a date, Madam Secretary.
If 28 continues for one month, that would be
Friday, February 6, 2026. Councilor
Soto Martinez. Yes. Happy New Year  To
everyone.
I want to call 29 special for
comments. Councilwoman Roman, I also
wanted to make a comment on that item.
Anyone else to my right, to the left
of the camera seeing that there are no
other specials. Madam Secretary,
what items can we vote on now?
The council can vote on item one,
as many as 3 through 8. Sir. Okay, we can
open the roll for those items, close
the roll, and count the votes. 14 in favor.
What else is there,
Mr. President?
The council would like to hear
testimonies or presentations.
Well, let's begin with testimonies.
First, this year's will be given by
Councilwoman Rodriguez
of the 7th Ward. Good morning,
colleagues and members of the public. Thank you
for joining us. Sadly, 2026 began
without a lack of chaos at the hands of a
federal administration that continues to
assault and inflict harm on
communities, not only here in Los
Angeles, but across the country.
Sadly, we just saw a woman
lose her life
at the hands of ICE. This is now the fifth
loss of life resulting from these
assaults.
conducted by AIS agents across the
country. But what's most infuriating,
aside from the assaults themselves, is the targeting of those
who are simply
protesting
or helping to document the actions
happening in communities across
the country.
We know the harm
inflicted on people in our
community, whose voices are
being ignored and whose families are being
torn apart.
This chaos continues to inflict tremendous damage
on America.
It's at the end of the year that we bring in
individuals like Memo Torres talking about
all the
incidents here in Southern
California.
But when I look at the footage, what
happened to René, a woman who had just
dropped her 6-year-old son off at school
, there's no way that does
n't affect all of us.
But this is all intended
to cause fear and harm to our
communities, to
enable the assaults that are
happening to
immigrant communities in this country and, frankly, to
citizens in this country, and we heard that
with René Goodman. I want to take a
moment to remind everyone
that while we don't have
direct authority
to  To prevent what the president is doing
and what is being permitted
by the federal leaders elected to
represent us,
if we have the opportunity to
document, monitor, and protect
our residents and demand
accountability for the actions that
occur in this city.
And I want to assure the public
that the silence in the
follow-up reports we seek to ensure there are
actions we can
take to protect members of
our communities, to see if they
are speaking out or documenting what
has happened here
in terms of the assaults against
our community members.
Now we are taking the gloves off. It is
happening, it happened last year, and it is
happening this year. So, in honor of
René Good and all the other individuals
directly affected and harmed by
ACE's actions, I would like to begin
this City Council meeting in
recognition of what continues to
happen in this country and, of course,
our city, and to ensure that
everyone recognizes and that all
Angelenos understand
that, at least for me,
as the elected leader representing
one of the 15 members of this
legislative body, I am not here to suggest
or pretend, nor should I be under
any  There's a misunderstanding that their
actions have been delayed because they haven't been
delayed. Don't normalize the action,
don't stop paying attention. They are still
a voice for change, and
I want to invite members of the
public to continue. I thank you
for coming and being that voice of
representation,
but we're going to have an election
soon, and I think it's important that
everyone remembers their civic outreach
and what this country has to stand for
and what this country has to stand for.
Thank you very much, Councilor Rodriguez. It's
a
very appropriate start
to our work here on the council
because of the seriousness of what's
happening in our community. The
next presentation will be
given by Councilor Hernandez
of the First Ward. Thank you, Mr.
Chair. We have some guests
here with us today. I'm going to give you a
minute to join us.
Thank you, Councilor Rodriguez, for your
words.
Lifting up René
Goodman.
Cg
was shot and killed by Ace.
Her death deserves justice and care,
but sometimes we show that we're not
committed to justice, we're
committed to convenience. What
happened to Kit Porter also deserves the
Attention, especially when it involves
ACE officers with a long history of
violence. This happened in our
own backyard, and silence is not an
option when it comes to naming this truth
and grounding ourselves in it. And to speak about
Keith, I'm going to invite Cordel Armstrong,
who was a member of
Keith Porter's family. Keith Porter was a father, a
neighbor, a beloved member of our
community who is
grieving and demanding justice. An
officer can't say who lives and
who dies. He can't be the judge in
every other part of this system.
It takes courage for families to
come here in the midst of their grief and
demand the truth. I'm so sorry for
your loss.
Please welcome Cordel
Armstrong. Speaking on behalf of K and his
family,
I'm going to invite his mother to
speak as well, to share a few words.
My son, Kid Porter, did not deserve this. Kid
Porter was a soul
with a huge heart. He had
such a big heart, he loved so much and so
deeply. Anyone who
came into contact with Kit loved him.
He was a joy. He was always cracking jokes,
he was my baby, he was a father, a  cousin, an
uncle and always said that the family,
especially
my son, would call me every morning to
say, "Good morning, mommy.  "I
love you." Every day before going to
work, before I even said "before
work," he would say to me, "Hi, Mommy, how
was your day?"
I miss my son so much.  He doesn't deserve
this.
His family, I am so grateful for
them.
He loved unconditionally, he never
argued, he never gossiped,
he always brought people together.  He was the type
of person who didn't get angry, he always
brought joy to the room, the way he walked, the way he
led the room, and he made
everyone feel special.
Everyone had a nickname; it came from joy
and love.  He would come to her house and cook, he would
cook something for her.  He wanted everyone to be
filled with joy.  He always
said, "I don't care if I don't
have a daughter.
I'm going to let everyone know that I'm
that person. Then I'm going to put my clothes on and
I'm going to love. I'm a
spiritual person. I love God. And I love
everyone, and there are a lot of people who love me, and
I know it. So, I just want
you to know, please, justice for my
baby. He doesn't deserve this.
This person hurt my son, and he would never have
hurt anyone. He loved so much;
he worked with disabled children and
helped raise families in
foster homes. He has such a loving heart,
such a big heart; he didn't deserve
this. He was going back to tell me, to
say, 'Mommy, I love you.' He did
n't even get to celebrate with champagne this
New Year's. He didn't even get to say, 'Goodbye.'"  I
want to hug my baby again and
hold him in my arms.
They took their lives.
God, please, I hope that you can please bring
justice for my son.
Please, justice for my baby.
Say your name Kter.
Dig porter.
Thank you.  I am Jamalen, the
lawyer for part of the family.
Echoing what we heard from her
mother, Kid is more than just a
newspaper headline.  He is a human being who gave love and
deserves justice and accountability.
What does justice look like?  Justice
begins by
revealing the name of the people from ACE.   We do
n't know his name, but we clearly
know that he was not acting under
any official duty.  This was not a
trained law enforcement officer
responding to a crime.  The
Los Angeles Police Department
was coming, and what we see with
K's murder is a microcosm of what's
happening in the country.  What
we see in Minnesota, in all
communities with
Black and Brown minority communities,
is officers committing crimes without
accountability, and today we demand,
we ask for that accountability.  Thank you.
Good morning.  I am Joseph Williams,
I am with
Black Lives Matter Los Angeles,
executive director of Student Serve.  He worked with
Keith's cousin, Jenet Tyler, who
let us know when Keith was killed
, when we had a visual on
Sunday, a vigil on Sunday and his
Home Depo colleagues were there.  He
worked at Home Depo for almost a year and
already had such a great impact on his
coworkers that dozens of
them came before
community organizing activists
to show their love and how deeply
he impacted them.
He was a person who was a father.  If
you look at his Instagram and social media,
everything was as he wanted his son, his
family, and his community.  And I also want to
say that yes, this is absolutely a
symptom of what is happening
nationally with the unfair enforcement of
immigration, harming immigrants and
many other people in our
communities, and it is not separate from what
is happening in this very city.
We know that in this city
,
police department shootings increased by 70%
last year and there was very little
accountability in any of those
cases.  The fact that
Kit, Keith Porter's killer, was not
arrested and forced to surrender his weapon
that night is unacceptable.  This man
murdered someone in cold blood,
someone celebrating
the new year, hoping his family would
join him in the celebration.  a
beloved father, community member, and
worker.  This is something that
the city council and the
entire city absolutely need to look at and say is
unacceptable.  It's not something we
can
point to and say is Donald Trump's fault
.  We need to look at
ourselves and say what policies in the city and
what investments we make with our
budgets are allowing
these things to happen, not only
federal agents, but also
local authorities.  And we know that
immigration is a black problem
too, that the harm that is
happening in our communities does not
only affect people who
come from Central and South America.
We know that the largest immigration enforcement
operation is happening
in Minnesota,
whitening
sub-Somali black immigrants.  And we know that the
white supremacist system depends on
indigenous lands and the oppression of blacks to
enrich the capitalist class.
Therefore, we ask that you, the
city council, do everything in your
power to hold the
authorities in this city accountable.  Using
the power you have to set
the budgets in this city and
hold the mayor accountable,
say that we need to invest in
responsibility, care, resources, and
support for our entire community, and that we need to
move money away from the
authorities who continue to harm our
communities with impunity.
Keith Porter's life matters.  Keith Porter's life
matters.  Kid Porter's life
matters and he deserves accountability.  Their
mothers, their friends don't have to be
here.  You shouldn't have to come here
while you're crying to say, "
Please direct the officers to arrest
the person who killed my son."  It
shouldn't be their responsibility.
It's all of you.  You have the
power to say that our
municipal employees, the police department,
have to be arresting any
officer.
harming our community.
So, we need to stop just
pointing fingers at Donald Trump
and say what we have, what is
within our power as the
City Council here to move forward with
real justice for
Keith Porter's family and the tens of thousands of other
families in communities
constantly harmed by
federal and local authorities.
So, we'll be here.
Continuing to demand justice for
Keith Porter and for all the other
people who have been robbed by
the authorities, kidnapped by the
authorities, harmed by the
authorities, because there are many.
Keith Porter's daughter is 9 years old, he has
a 20-year-old daughter, and they are going to live
the rest of their lives without their father.  There is
nothing anyone in this room
can do to get justice for Kid
Porter, because that would mean he
would be here with his family.  But what we
can do is move forward and
demand accountability from the
people who stole his life without
justice.   He
shouldn't be walking around yet, he shouldn't
be anonymous yet.  Everyone should know
who this man was, what he looks like, and what
his name is.  And he has to be in
jail, he has to be facing
charges.  So we urge all of
you to use the power you
have
as the city council in the
largest city in the country.  While
fascism is advancing in the country,
while the authorities and terror
are advancing throughout the country, what are
you going to do?  What are you going to do
?  Not in directions, letters, or
social media.  What are they going to do with the
power and positions they hold to
demand real justice?
responsibility for a different future
in a different world for life, for
Kid Porter's family,
black families and immigrant families throughout
the city.  We will continue to
fight for justice in
Kid Porter's name for his family and
continue to demand that all of you
in positions of power, being elected
by the people of this city, do what you
have to do with the power and
positions you have
to fight against the
fascist regime, advancing harm from the
authorities and terror here and throughout the
country.
These are
difficult times and all of you need to
take extraordinary measures to demand
accountability and transparency and
do something different with the resources we
have available here.
President Trump is defunding
education and public services that
our communities depend on
and has created the largest authority entity
in the history of this country.
So, it is unacceptable that this
council also voted to increase
funding for the authorities, the
police department.  These things are
not disconnected, they are
connected.  So, we stand here in
solidarity with the family of Kid
Porter,
the family and community of René Good, the
people shot yesterday in Portland, and
all the people shot and killed
and robbed of their families, and all of
you here on the City Council
have the power and responsibility to
take action.  Regarding this, I would like to
give it my full
understanding.  My condolences to Kid
Porter's mother, Mrs. Armstrong.  Thank you so much
for being here today.
Thank you to everyone in the community for your
words, for your
time, and for allowing us to share.
Say his name, Kid Porter.  Say his
name, Kid Porter.  Say his name, Kid
Porter.
Thank you, councilors, uh, councilors
Rodríguez and Hernández,
for starting with these testimonies,
both of you.  And to the point made by Councilor
Rodríguez, uh,
the importance of these testimonies.
We see that they are getting worse, not
better.  We are seeing the community
kidnapped, detained, a murder on
the highway, and now people murdered in
cold blood.
We will continue to shed light on this
problem.  So again, thank you
councilwomen Rodríguez Hernández and
Kid Porter's family who
joined us today.  No, council members, uh,
let's see, today is uh the first meeting
of the year 2026, and as many of you remember,
uh, the first meeting of the year 2025 is
a day that we will remember forever
in the city of Los Angeles when we were
visited,
excuse me, when we saw uh one of the
most tragic days we have seen in
the history of our city, uh, when we
saw damage to our property and the
loss of life.
Therefore, and to
remember and mark this time of the
2025 fires that affected us so much
here in Los Angeles and in Pacific
Palates, the San Fernando Valley and in
Malibu, Altadina, also in the county.
I want to call,
uh, to start with the
commemoration of this time with our
own councillor Tracy Park.
Good morning everyone.  Thank you
, Mr. President, for allowing me to
begin this presentation on January 7,
2025, about the
horrific fires that damaged the
communities of Pacific Palestine and
Altadina.  In Pacific Palestine we lost
12 lives in Altadena, and
another 19
tragic deaths
across Los Angeles.
We continue to keep families close to
our hearts.  Please
join me
in a brief moment of silence for
these lives that were lost that day.
Thank you.
A year ago,
on Wednesday,
our city experienced the worst
disaster we have seen in the
last 240 years.  The day began like
any other.  For us it was a day
of advice
as we traveled through various
parts of the city.  Many of us,
like me, spent
a few minutes on Kanex, a few calls
asking us what drama we were going to watch
that day for thousands of other residents.   It
was the same sending the children to
school, dragging the trash cans to
the sidewalks,
saying goodbye to the dog and
running to work without knowing it would be
the last time.
The last time we weren't going to see a
formal goodbye.
Chief Cy called me during the meeting,
our meeting, to inform me that there was
a fire inside Palisates and
that it was growing rapidly.
She spoke calmly, but suggested
that I return to the West Side as soon as
possible.
Councilwoman Ram already had a fire
within the district, uh, four.  We
were already wondering how bad
things were going to get.  I also
remember that, Mr. President, you offered me, you
offered me to return to the
west to be with
my constituents.  And when I arrived,
the firestorm had already
arrived.
The air was filled with smoke.  We could barely
breathe
the wind from
all directions.
The firefighters were going all over the
community, but just hours
before, things had been
calm.
The firefighters were trying to fight
a fire that they couldn't, they didn't have
the power, we hadn't seen anything like it before.
Thousands of firefighters from 400
departments across
Los Angeles County, California, the
United States, Mexico, and Canada
came to support Los Angeles.  At the
same time, evacuation orders were already being
torn apart,
communication systems were not working,
we lost power, traffic lights were out with so
many cars trying to get out of
Malibu and Pacific Palest onto
Highway One.
Lots of traffic while the fires were burning
in the mountains.
Those who could not leave by car
escaped on foot.  I will never
forget all those people
trying to escape from Palis to the
beach,
carrying only what they could
as they left and the fires
continued.
The entire village was burning
one by one.  Their homes, their churches,
their schools,
their businesses,
all the things,
everything that defines a community that
creates a neighborhood,
just within a couple of hours
they disappeared.
Finally, the losses are too many
to count, the
devastation too great to quantify,
and the wound will take a long time to heal.
Many no longer have
anything to return to.  Nothing can
prepare us, or anyone,
for a day like that.
But what happened after the fire is
also something impressive.
What propelled the community forward,
and what followed a year later
, was not just one thing or one
institution, it
was the people.
While roads remained closed
and families remained separated,
the community of Palis did what they
had always done.   They
supported each other, not just because
they were told to, not because there was a plan,
but
they simply understood, they understood that the community
would be the first way to be able to
survive and also
the foundation to be able to survive.
Each neighbor would
communicate with another neighbor to see
who was still there.
They supported each other, opened their
homes, and began to re-establish
human connections before they could even
imagine
restarting construction on the
buildings.  Residents organized themselves block by block
when there was no
plan.
They met to understand
bureaucratic procedures that
felt impossible to navigate
individually.
These people coordinated with the
community to move forward
together.
When this seemed difficult, and it was,
the neighbors came together to continue
supporting each other and moving
forward, even on occasions when the
easiest thing would have been to give up.
There were meetings to address
insurance issues, delayed calls,
emails
in the mornings, and
enormous, hard work that no news report will be
able to capture, but all of this would not have
been possible otherwise.
This coordination lasted not just for a
couple of days, but for months.  This
work continues to this day.
There are so many Padians who have carried and
moved the community forward.  I can't
name everyone, but many are here
today.
Jessica Rogers Lorzo, Kim Fedter Sam
Regana Alison Holdor Paul Hill Sirlock
Hmman,
Carol David Ross,
Dapne Gronic Larry Vin Pastor
Marden, Noah Martin Bart Sherry Mandel Rosan
Lande Lean Sanderson,
Mark Smith, Evanhall Michelle Safrad
Brown Paul.
In this community, she didn't do it alone.
In the days and hours that followed, the
communities through the angels.
They opened their communities, their schools,
their homes, and their hearts.   So
many families were left without
homes, volunteers,
first responders, donation centers,
emergency centers, and
trucks arrived.
Angelenos across the city
donated their time and donations without being
asked,
and they did so before the
governing systems could even begin.  Also
for months after the fires, FEMA
and the Red Cross arrived to support
families and businesses under the
extraordinary leadership of Colonel Eric
Swensen.   They
not only cleared the rubble, but
they created hope and gave us
a way to return home.  Okay,
we're going to watch a video now and look back
to January 7th and the
months that followed.
What was lost in these fires was not
just property, it was places,
houses full of history,
gifts, gifts from grandparents,
memories,
memories from parents, and dreams,
dreams that children had.
This fire took away not only
structures, but also parts of our
history.
A year ago, Los Angeles experienced the
worst disaster we have seen in its
240-year history.  In just a couple of
hours, an entire community was
devastated.  Twelve people lost their
lives, thousands of homes were lost,
schools,
churches, the library, businesses, the
Sunset Historic Corridor,
historic sites were reduced to rubble,
and then the community
supported each other and Los Angeles
supported Palisates.
In the months that followed,
government departments came to support the
community by opening the roads.  Fima
and Army Core did something
extraordinary, not only cleaning up
plots in historical time, but
also creating the next steps
for a community desperate to
move forward.  This was urgent, it was
humane.  It was about stabilizing an
entire community while the ground
beneath our feet was
collapsing.
This
area has received the worst
damage due to this fire that
took almost all of these houses
within this area.  I was here on
that day, January 7th, with
members of the community.  Uh,
we knew that we saw chaos that day,
obviously we saw the
news reports, but we don't really know
what was happening.
We arrived and saw that there were a lot of people
putting things into their cars and we
immediately said to ourselves, "Well,
let's get there and take
action."   We
were knocking on doors, helping
people get down the hill and I'll never
forget that day we were covered
in smoke and ashes and the councilwoman gave
each of us a hug.
I would like to return to the
original fire in the Palesides.
We have here her co-host who is
going to talk to us about what
happened that day, uh, when she thinks about those
moments, uh, trying to decide what to
take with her.
Sure, we've seen vacations
before, but during these moments of
panic you try to take what you
can, what do I have to take,
and that took almost an hour and at one point you
have to tell yourself, we have to
go, get in the car and leave.  I would say
that day it was around 2:30 in the
afternoon.  From what I understand, the fire
arrived around 7 o'clock on my neighbor's
Alphabet Street.  And looking
back,
uh, part of me asks why,
why didn't I run away so quickly,
and sometimes I say that I should have stayed
behind because you know when you
lose your home in a disaster like this one we
experienced, it's not just your
house, but all those things we've
collected throughout our lives, the
memories, the children, the books, we've all, we're all still
dealing with this trauma.
They decimated our entire community.
We are a very close-knit community.   It
felt like an extended,
uh, separated family.   It
was very difficult, very difficult and very
sad.
Tichan Terce is a mobile community in
the Pacific Palace that has foundations
in the 1960s.  It was a
retirement home.
Eventually, the community voted to
turn it into an all-
ages park.  My son was the first baby
born in that park.  There wasn't a
single person living there who did
n't understand how
good it was to have them living there in
that park.
I want to remind you that this is a
special place.  Uh, we formed a
long-term recovery group.
Um, my list of uh families is 460
families and my role is to connect with these
people,
whether they are uh that they are
well or that they have lost everything,
when they have nothing left, when everything was
destroyed in the fire.  The
hardest thing for me has been
understanding that I have to add a
psychological component
to support each family before
trying to
restart and rebuild.
Many plots have been cleared
due to the work of the Army Core.  We've
seen a lot of activity here in the
alphabets, especially since this area
has suffered a lot of damage.  The
constituents have filled out their
forms.  We've seen trucks
going in and out of the parks.  What
we are doing today is taking
access and clearing the debris from the
fire.  What really amazed
me was seeing the Army Core.  They
achieved miracles.   We
really had a lot of problems,
we faced problems as a community,
but now we can look to the future
for the potential to
rebuild and restart.   I
miss you all so much and
you usually think
when I was there a couple of
weeks ago, I drove through the Palace
and saw firsthand how
resilient the community is.   It
warmed my heart and I would like to
thank every member of the
community for making my time there so
special.  I truly feel connected to
you all
and I
am grateful to be able to help each
resident restart.   It's been
almost a year now and I look
back on those early days and what
happened afterwards and the fear of
robberies.  In the first few days after the
fire, my house, well, we went through what was
left of the house.
Uh, it's like a feeling of, uh, a
violation of
your rights, of your things.  We have
worked
with LPD to search homes, give
orders not to install
camera systems in place, and we are creating
more.  Let's continue with
open minds.  And by being so much more creative together
we can survive this.  I
have so much, so much hope for
Palestine, we are resilient, we
care for each other, our community
is strong and we are committed to
returning to our homes.  before the
fires.  My youngest son
liked gardening,
and before the house burned down, there was
a piece of garden that would later
become his garden. After the
fire, we met a neighbor,
and that same day she took three of
these tomatoes that she had
in her bag, and that day she
gave them to us.  And we planted these
roots again.  And I have plans
to return, as does my neighbor who is
94 years old.  This is going to be a day of a
lot of help, a lot of faith,
and that's what this represents for me.
The Pacific Palestinians refuse to be defined
by this day, but this community
is still healing and we still need help.
As a city, we remain
committed to honoring what remains
and to carrying on with the
difficult work that follows.
The video summarizes the incredible work and
courage that so many people
demonstrated in facing
immense sadness and
overwhelming devastation.  Much of that work was done
by hundreds of dedicated
municipal workers.  Several
municipal departments worked to restore
order, security, and basic services.
Emergency management coordination responses were made under
extreme pressure and extraordinary dispatch.   The
police department maintained
security and offered
relief
to the already devastated community.
They stabilized critical infrastructure
and the construction and
security department.  They're working too
hard.   The
Sanitation Department removed
trash, trees, and millions of nails
from our roads, facing
landslides, storms, and
floods.  His work
helped prevent further damage and loss.
It's part of a very appreciated piece of advice.
I want to extend my thanks to our
incredible city family for their
dedication, for their commitment to serving
the residents after this tragedy.
Now we're going to look at some of the
employees' names, part of this
response, the
fire department responders, and I want to
read some names who, at the request
of Mayor Karen Bas, went there
to help at the recovery centers
and on-site: the
aging department, the
building and safety department, the
cannabis regulation department, the
city manager's office, the
City Tourism Department,
Los Angeles Airport, the
Animal Services Department, the
Legislative Analyst's office, the
city attorney's office, the
civil and human rights department
, the Comptroller's office,
cultural affairs, disabilities,
The People of Los Angeles, the
historic landmark, and the
emergency management department.
Fire and Police Department and
Pensions, General Services Department
, Ethics Commission, Finance,
Firefighters,
Public Libraries, Laza,
Housing Authority,
Information Technology Agency,
Lasers,
Housing Department,
Public Accountability,
Personnel Department, Police Department.
Public Works,
Mayor's Office,
Neighborhood Empowerment Department,
Municipal Planning Department,
Contract Administration Office, Engineering,
Street Services,
Recreation and Parks,
Water and Energy,
Child Development Department,
Sanitation Office,
Street Lighting Office,
Public Transportation,
Municipal Secretary's Office.
Community investment for the
families department,
economic development department,
Port of Los Angeles, Los
Angeles Zoo, colleagues, perhaps those were
all the departments in the city of
Los Angeles, who helped,
whose dedicated employees and
time and resources and heart and grit.
I also want to take a moment,
colleagues, to thank you all.
Some joined the PIDS on the day of
the fires, and others came days
later to stay by my side
to witness what happened.  Others of
you lent your
outreach and reception teams and staff to
answer our phones and respond
to emails,
welcome people in, and staff
our donation centers so
that my team could focus on the
devastation in front of us.
Those first few days were the most
difficult of my career, of my life
really, but my colleague's generosity and
support illuminated
or made, unloaded my burden
and guided me to do everything necessary to
help stabilize
a traumatized and displaced community.
Then, Council President Haris
Dosen, Councilor Lee, Councilor
Rodriguez, Councilor Jaroslovski, Councilor
H, Councilor
Hernandez, Councilor Romen,
Councilor Padilla,
Councilor Price,
Councilor Soto Martinez,
Councilor Mov, Councilor Jury
on behalf of Council District 11.
Thank you for your support during these times and
now as well,
and that now brings me
my incredible team.
I am
so
impressed by the ways you have
helped our residents over the past
year.
After the fires that you all
worked on every day.
Without their
off-hours commitments, every
week, they
paused their lives to serve
our residents, our city.
His actions were nothing short of
heroic, and a simple thank you will not
suffice.
Several members of my team
were on site, in the
burn zone.
Ais Gregorian was working her
second day with my office as our
representative
for Pacific Palace.  Have your first
constituent coffee in the Palestines
when the fire started,
you didn't wait
for anyone to direct you
and tell you what to
do.  You
were there in the middle of it all.
You
went to the neighborhood and started saving
lives
while rescuing residents
who needed help.
Juan Fregoso,
Juan Fregoso, I don't see him.  There in front of
me is Juan,
my district director.
an incredible team that went from
Westchester to the fire zone.
Juan led Johan Silva, Trake Rogan,
Julio Torres, and Martín Pérez Pérez,
both of whom were on their second
day on the job in District 11, on a
mission crossing the Palestinian territories
together.
Those six incredibly
brave people went door to door
evacuating residents,
rescuing, carrying animals and watering
roofs, burning bushes, literally
saving
homes and lives.
The District 11 team. You
literally risked your lives to
save and protect others.  His bravery
is nothing short of
outstanding.   I
was on a command post, I
was on the PCH Command Post
during the fire and communications
were blocked and I was so worried
about you because I couldn't get in
touch with any of you on your
phones as the hours went by.  I was so
worried and I'll never
forget how relieved I was when
you all finally came out together with
a group walking,
leaving the Palace on foot walking
through PCH.  Those hugs we shared
came from the depths of my soul.
While the fire burned for days
afterward, this team returned to the
fire zone.  They returned by fixing up
animals, putting out fires, fixing up
with survivors, who never
left the Palestinians, and bringing
supplies to first responders
and more.
Without being asked, they went to get
things that needed to be done, and they did
those things.  And meanwhile,
at City Hall, my
legislative team made up of Kevin Bronky and
Sarah Flattery,
the planning director, Craig
Bullock, and Craig Isara,
were also on their second day on the
job in District 11. They began to take
action by talking to other cities
that had gone through these disasters,
meeting with government and legislative agencies
to coordinate next steps, and
writing the dozens of motions that
started our disaster response
and laid the foundation for the
recovery we
are now in.  My advisor Jacob
Berman, the operations center for several
weeks, brought the most
up-to-date information to keep the
news updated as
circumstances changed day by day.
Michael Hamster, Manamden, Carol
Williams, Casey Pratz, and Greginen
helped
set up supply and
evacuation centers and set up a massive
donation center,
while Elder Barel and William Mayala
answered hundreds of calls at the
Westchester office.
Steve Conor worked day and night
coordinating dozens of hearings,
site visits, and constituent build-ups
that flooded our
calendars.  The communications team P
Brown and J La Laguna worked hard
keeping our residents
updated and informed,
and my
amazing chief legislator staff.
Lord, you led us through it all,
kept us moving
as a united team,
managing the constituents,
managing me,
and doing it all
with grace, incredible humility.
under
incredibly difficult circumstances,
personally difficult.  I could have
chosen a more important angel in a
city of angels to have by my side.
Colleagues, it's been a full-court press conference
.  that didn't come out for months and
still hasn't come out.  Team, it makes me so
proud to serve our city,
proud of our work together and
all of you,
for doing your amazing jobs in
all of this and the unique contributions
that you have all made.  You
inspire me to do everything I do, and I
couldn't do this job without you,
and I wouldn't want to.
So, colleagues and friends, we all
know that recovery doesn't happen in
just one year, while progress
cannot be denied, but for many families
the hardest part is still to come.
Thousands are sailing,
Ansas and Mortgages are expiring and
people are getting lost, they are
running out of time.   We
deserve urgent statements to
the victims and a
long-term commitment to restoring what was lost.
Every neighborhood in Los Angeles is just
one disaster away from
devastation.
Being ready is not a luxury, and investing in
recovery cannot be optional.
The lesson in this tragedy cannot be
about what went wrong, it has to be about what
we do to make it right.  We honor
the past, protecting the future,
moving forward together with purpose,
intention, and resolve.  Thank you, Mr.
Chairman of the Council.
Thank you so much, Councilor Park and
District 11 team. I know that
some Angelenos from the
Palestides neighborhood got together.  So, thank you for
sharing this morning with us during
one of the saddest days
in our city's history.  And
then, if the
members want to comment, they
can do so at this time.  If we can't
move to public comments now
.
Very good.
Well, before I make any
public comments, I want to call District 1
for an additional introduction.
We also met this morning with
several general managers with the
recognition department.  Thank you for
being here as well.
Okay, let's get started now.  Good morning
everyone.
Good morning everyone.  We are here to
celebrate the career of someone who
has literally changed the
face of Los Angeles for 25 years.
Wrop, chief representative for the
engineering office, is retiring.
Born in Mexico City and educated
at Princony Berkeley, Debora joined
the engineering office in 2001.
She served as the first woman in the
architecture division and the first
architect to serve as the
city engineer.  It's literally
breaking through
concrete ceilings.  Whether you walked along the
Los Angeles River or the Sixto
Debra Bridge.  And for us in district
one, the impact was personal.  For a long
time they saw other districts
having high-quality parks, and Deborah
helped us
with Taylor Yards.  If you didn't go to
Taylor's gardens, there's a lot of work to be done to make it
accessible to everyone, but it's
beautiful to support the initiative to
reconnect MC Park and the new
beginnings
being part of a rehabilitation,
revitalization of the Los Angeles River,
but more than anything, her joy, the excitement
she felt seeing the communities
finally receive what they have been
fighting for for a long time.  Fight and
get results.  We went to several
beginnings in just my first
term.  This is the kind of spirit that
Tebora brought to her work every day,
a presence that will be missed in
this building, in the city, and in
District One.  The city of Los Angeles
will miss her presence,
at least she will have more time for
her family, her husband David and her children
Mika Aon and her
grandson Odes.  Deborah, you are a legend.
His legacy
will last for generations.
Thank you for your service and I hope
you can enjoy yourself
and make the best memories for
you and your family, but don't forget about
us because we still have a lot of
work to do.  And now I
want to invite Alfred Mata, the
mid-level engineer with the
engineering office.
Good morning.  Today is a day of
very strong emotions.  We are here to
commemorate Demora and wish him all the best
in his retirement.
During my time working within
the city.  Uh, I feel very grateful
to work with such successful people.  Uh, that
's a perfect example that fits
within that description.
We have had the pleasure of working
with Debra for the past few years.
She has a degree from Princeton
Berkeley and has worked with
architectural firms.  She has led
several projects
and is recognized for her
revolutionary design.
She was the main author of the
First Screen policy.  Undoubtedly, she has left her mark throughout
the city and during
her retirement.  As she moves
forward, she will be able to enjoy
her projects, including the Los
Angeles River, exhibits from
zoos, gyms, schools,
recreation centers, and even retaining walls.
in a note with a personal note.  I have
had the pleasure of working with Debrá
within the executive team and I have seen and
appreciated everything she has done.   She
not only
thinks about the design of the projects
, but also about the people
she works with.
She always gives great advice and
Debra,
we're very sad to see her go,
but we're very happy for
you, for David, for your daughter and the
newest addition, Oris.  I am so
grateful for what he has done for the
engineering bureau and wish him all the best
in his retirement.  Congratulations.
Now we're going to hear from
Debra, please, a few words.  It's a
sad day and I have mixed emotions
about my retirement, but I have
loved working for the city.  The
projects have been special.
My specialty, and what I always say, is that
design matters, and I believe I
bring this aspect to every project, whether it's
walls or small parks, and I
hope this city continues to see how
valuable design is in order to
improve our communities.  I
thank you all for your
collaboration.  It has been a pleasure working
with this council and the city council, and I look forward to the
future.  I hope to see this one continue
this good work.  When I started 25
years ago it was like my fifth career
and they told me as an architect that I would
love working for the
engineering bureau.   It has
been truly fantastic and
thank you very much councilors.  Thank you.
I would like to offer my colleagues, to give my
colleagues the opportunity, a few
words.  Thank you.  Let's start with
councilor.
Thank you, Mr. President, thank you
Councilor Hernandez for bringing
forward this recognition
as a resident of the Valley, which
has inspired me as a
young councilor who had many questions and
also as an adult.  Now that I still have
questions, thank you very much for
your contributions.
I look forward to seeing you, but seeing you
in Studio City, at Café Coyote, and
all the best to you and your
family.  Now I hope I can spend
more time with them.  Thank you for your
service, honorable.  Thank you, Councilor
Rodriguez.
Thank you, Councilor Hernandez, for
bringing Debra forward.
Uh, I've had the pleasure and benefit of
working with you for over a
decade, haven't I?  Oh, I forgot how
fast time flies. If
you really care about design, and what I
appreciate most about you is
that you understand it matters to all
parts of the city, no matter the
area, and so I really appreciate
this view of equality.  and that all
communities received the
same investment they deserve.  I know
we had many conversations about her
family and
all these things, and these
impressive lives she has lived.  So I
wish him all the best.  Thank you for your
service here in the city and for
your friendship and congratulations.  Uh, a
retirement that really deserves just
another reminder of what we're
losing.
What I do know is that you have done an
impressive job, as have
all the
other leaders, ensuring that there is
a plan in place to follow behind
you and
to maintain the same
commitment you have to this
service.  So thank you very much and it was a
pleasure working with you.
Thank you, councilman.  Ah, thank you, Councillor
Price.  Thank you Councilor Hernandez for
bringing a live angel here.
Their projects within District 9
have been so impressive.
You are not only concerned with the
architectural integrity of the
structures, but also with the impacts
on the community, so you
have always kept an eye on both.
So thank you very much for this,
Councilor Ramal.   I
also want to thank you, Deb.
Thank you for so many years of service and
to acknowledge that this council has
worked closely with you.  their voice and
their advice on our priorities.   They have been
met with the utmost respect,
because we know that
whatever you work on,
whatever project you work on, will be done
in the best way possible.
And as I said, all the retirements we
've seen recently, if
we're really losing someone
with experience
in the
procedures, how
this city works, which is really
complicated, but I hope... I
just want to say that their presence will be
missed.
We are truly grateful as a city for
you,
councillor. Something that has been said more than
once over the years is that we have
asked for key members from within the
Burgos,
but at least Debor is still there.
This retirement is so well-deserved because
I know how
hard you've worked.
You have always had your hands in
all these projects.  So on behalf
of all the residents of District 12,
thank you.  Thank you,
councilman.
Thank you, Mr. President.  Councilman
Hernandez.
Deborah, thank you for so many years of
service.  District 14 wouldn't be the same
without your work, so I hope you'll come
celebrate the park this summer.
Thanks also for introducing us to
Heid, we have some great ideas on how to
collaborate together.
This city, you can really see,
figuratively
and literally, how their
work is demonstrated.  Thank you, councilor, sworn,
thank you from Verora for your service.  It has
been an invaluable contribution to the
city.  I just want to tell
a short story about a
project that maybe you won't even
remember, but during my first few weeks
in my job I took them to
a building and said, "This is how
our office should look, but there's no
way the city is going to be
able to achieve it."  And you looked me straight in
the eye and said, "Yes,
this project can be done."
It turned out to be a great project. So much so
that when
people come in, many people say, "How
can the city afford
such a beautiful building in this city?"
The details you've put into the
design. I always hear your name mentioned
when residents talk
about it. So thank you, thank you for
dedicating this part of your life to
making things more beautiful for
everyone.
Thank you, colleagues, Mr. President,
all the families, friends, and
colleagues who are with us today.
Please join me in saying goodbye to Debora.
We have here a resolution signed by the
entire Council, recognizing her legendary status
and her contribution to the city's history. So
please join me in giving a round of applause for
Debra.
Well,
thank you, Councilor Hernandez,
a great presentation. Now I'm going to ask
the City Attorney to prepare us
for public comment. Yes, for
everyone providing public comment.
When it's your turn, please state  You can choose
which point you'd like to discuss. You'll
have up to one minute per point, for a
total of three minutes. We'll
let you know when your time is up. You
must stay on topic. Our
goal is to hear from everyone who wants to
speak. If you stray from the topic or if we can't
resolve it while you're on
topic, we'll give you an
initial warning.
If you can't focus on the topic, you'll
lose the rest of your time
for public comment. The points
currently open for public comment are items 9 through 27
and 29 through 31. Again, the points
open for public comment on
the agenda are items 9 through 27 and 29
through 31. Item 28 has been carried over
to February, so it's not
open for public comment.
Members of the public can also
speak on general comment; they can
talk about any point or anything
else within the jurisdiction of
the City of Los
Angeles.
Good morning. If you require
Spanish translation services, and if you are
speaking, please  Please be sure to take a
brief pause so the interpreters
can translate. Thank you.
And don't worry, time will be
paused, and you will receive the same
amount of time as everyone else.
Thank you.
Under the office
needs services. Uh,
accommodation services have been requested. Uh, please
notify an officer. So, the
names we're going to call are
varied.
Please wait until you hear your
name before coming to the podium. After
you hear your name, you may line up
to the left of the camera.
I'm going to start calling the names.
Karina, Laura, Chenan, Andrea, and Dangas.
There's one person, Mr. Alman. Please
follow the instructions I've given you at
this meeting, and you may sit there
until your wireless microphone is brought to you
. We've received your
accommodation request, but please
follow these rules. We're going to take the
first speaker to the podium.
Good morning. Please come forward. Uh,
general comment.
Uh, elected officers,
we assume you're going to
raise your hands.  Their voices on the things that
matter most to them. But there's an exception
when it comes to extortion.
People know they're victims, and they know
the officers who should be
protecting them are refusing to take
action.
We need to write a letter to the
governor to investigate
police conduct. He's not going to
risk stepping on the
officers' toes. It really is his
responsibility. I don't know what they're
talking about during the closed session, but
I suspect they're being told not to
help.
I'd like to call on C. Horit, Ky Leon,
Steven Jerry C, Maduro, Nick and Jules
Murphy, Simon, and
Harry Elliot. Good morning. You have three
minutes, plus one for test, test,
test.
I want to talk about all the points and
general public comment. What's
my time? Okay, [ __ ]. So,
I think it's three minutes.
I'm starting the
teams on
14.
It's about point number three. Number
three is not open for
public comment. If you notice, the points
we talked about earlier on the agenda
are points 9 through  27
and 2731. Your only warning. Please
stay on topic for the
next 2 minutes.
Go ahead.
So, smoke. Item number 30,
civil rights,
immigration. Thank you Donald J. Trump for,
uh, aging and disabilities and
public safety by David
Carter, who just gave the city of
Los Angeles
a fine in the millions of
dollars for doing nothing.
Yes,
the accused impersonating,
uh, local officers with
his group known as LASA. We
know that people under the guise of being
public safety officers have
done nothing, not a [ __ ] thing
for housing. Ma'am, this is not
related to item 30. This is going to
be your final warning. Stay on
topic or I'm going to cut your
time. So you're telling me
this isn't about the item. Can you
please clarify what the response would be?
This is not, uh,
this is not within this item.
[ __ ], [ __ ] the
local police who are accusing
individual people or property in any other
[ __ ] way they can  be understood.
Honestly, [ __ ] off
, uh, huge head.
Can you talk about my head for the
next minute? We gave you several warnings and you did
n't stay on topic, so
general comment. Okay. Gavison,
ladies and gentlemen, has announced that
now is the time for mayors to
clean up the housing crisis. If
you think that's like me saying, I have a
huge dick in my hand. The only
dick is pointing at all of you
for messing around to help the
homeless and creating a crisis that David
Carter, a federal judge,
a judge who in his stupid laws
that don't help, like that
idiot governor who doesn't help Trump. Thank you,
Donald Trump, for helping America.
Donald Trump has done a
phenomenal job for this country.
Which has allowed, Mr. Herman, your
time has expired. Next speaker,
please.
Good morning. What topics do you want to discuss?
No topic. Public comment.
Uh,
on the I live closer on STH and
Wilsher and there is a neighbor who  He has
an apartment that has—how do I say this?—he
has a large amount of garbage
accumulated in his front door, and
because he hasn't gone to pick it up in
a while, there's no one living there.
Thank you.
In John Dean's book, he says that
there is confidential information.
He has erased his previous criminal
records with help from the government.
Under seven
speakers before the next
speaker begins.
Dan Edgar, Neighbors, Jim G, and Cesar Lopez.
Good morning. What topics would you like to
discuss? General comment.
This is public time, not
coffee break time. Half of the representatives
left.
Close
the Los Angeles Central Jail. The
Los Angeles Central Jail should be closed. And
before we begin with the next
commentator, all members of the
public are going to ask that you please refrain from
blowing a whistle into the
microphone. We have employees
who have hearing problems, and it can
damage their hearing, and it's not necessary. It's a
whistle; we can hear it. Good morning.
What topics would you like to discuss? Hello, I
'm Kil La  Funa, general comment.
A year ago, we were on fire, and I
saw the city come together here in
ways that move me, ways that
only we will ever
understand. None of you told
people they needed to do their best.
Learning to have real power to
do the best they could to help
their neighbors. While cleaning up the
ashes, the federal government attacked our
city, and I came here begging for
help,
pleading with you to please support the
legend, not terrified by Ray.
You ignored me and all of
us. The City Council's message has
been to put the blame on the people, the
responsibility on us to be
peaceful, which we always have been, not the
federal government or the
police department. Roberto Valdés was killed by
Acea,
which implies that he is to blame.
With the hand, TR was arrested for
watching Ice leaving the island, they did
nothing. The message they send is that
documenting them from a safe distance is at
their own risk. Everyone loves to
say that Los Angeles is a place of
analysis.  Everyone loves to say that Los
Angeles isn't running
its clock, and actually, its
general public comment period has expired. If you keep
talking about Ice's radars, you can
speak for topics 29
and 30, so you have two minutes for those
topics. Go ahead.
Everyone loves to say that Los Angeles
is the testing ground. And we are.
Reneg died because of inaction here.
I and 100 other people were warned
that this was going to happen. Kid Porter
died
the night before New Year's Eve, and nobody
said anything. Not the mayor, nobody said
a [ __ ]. I
'm begging you. Please,
[ __ ] the quorum. Do things
differently. We need something to believe in.
Come out on the streets with us after
months of being brutalized by the
police. The city is conditioned to
stay in your homes and not fight.
You helped make that happen. Please
don't post on social media about
where the presses are. Please,
I'm begging. Do it
differently. We
need you. We need someone to
do something.  Look what happened last night in
Chicago. The people here are ready to
support you, but we've been told that
if we come,
we'll be shot, that the
police department will
physically assault us, not even the
federal authorities. We need something
to believe in. Give us something to believe in. This is
still the testing site. You
can change it, and I'm begging,
please.
Next. Obrador, good morning.
What topics would you like to discuss? Good
morning, sir.
All the topics, gentlemen, because at 2:30 PM, I'll cover
public safety, and
also everything related to it. I can
finish, sir, in 3 minutes. The
topics are 9 through 27 and 29 through 31.
So, give me everything, sir. Let's start
with public safety and the officers. I
mentioned it earlier, we have the
best police chief,
McDonald. Many may not like him,
but when you talk about someone prepared
to do a job to keep
the city safe, Chief McDonald is that
person. I personally have to
say, sir, Mr. McDonald, what
has happened? God gave you the
opportunity to do that  Let this city be
safer. It gave him the opportunity to do
good. Well, to see the people in this
city who are doing things
wrong. That's not the law, that's a crime. I
'm not being disrespectful, and I'm not
afraid of you, sir. I respectfully
ask that you please, please make
this city safer and do everything
to protect our citizens. With all due
respect, can I talk about the fires
in Pales? That was an issue. Yes, well, I'm not
going to talk about it.
Anyway, he's not listening.
It's nice to see that everyone was meeting,
watching the fires. I couldn't remember the other fire
because I'm old, but
everyone wants to do something. Where were
you all earlier?
This morning when I had to get
up because my back trees fell
down because there were
65-mile-per-hour winds knocking my trees down
in the yard.
We can't do anything about the
wind and the rain, right? But what do
you do? You give him
the match that's going to set
Puerto Ranch on fire. What topic are you
talking about?
Command, Mr. Candid, I'm going to
ask you again what topic you're
discussing.
Sir, do you want to go to general public comment
? Okay, you have one minute. Okay,
sir, I want to be respectful, but stop
doing that. You're acting like
this is ridiculous. We're leaving now.
What's going on at P Ranch? Everyone
's worried about the trees
falling down,
and I'm still worried about the
fire that's going to happen. Everyone comes
here to Palas—I do
n't remember exactly—but they're
here again. They have the opportunity to
do something, but yet they're still
allowing illegal parking at P
Ranch, tearing up
the area with
speeding cars. Do you know how many people have crashed
there? I have 60-mile-per-
hour winds, but I have cars going 80
miles per hour driving to
IT Park. And what are you doing
about this, John Lee? I'm going to
report you. You're watching. I was a
constituent there for years, and you can't
look me in the eye, can you?
You keep wearing that nice suit. But
I worked hard for my house. I came  From
the streets of Los Angeles to Puerto Ranch,
and I never forgot where I came from. Well,
your time is up. Next
commentator. Mr. Candido, you
are disrupting this meeting because we
cannot continue with this.
Your time is up. You need to leave
the stand.
I'm going to ask the gentleman with the
beard and the whistle, please don't blow
the whistle again, or we're going to
remove him.
Mr. Candido, you have already received your
first brief reprimand.
Next commentator. Yes.
Hello, good morning. It has to do
with me being
disabled, not just me, but
everyone.
If you have a minute.
What I want to do is for the
Vance area.
We really need
safety for us because I was
hit by a car.
Hit by a car, and
in January,
and I had to go to a
hospital. That
was
the idea.
I live between two buildings, and there was
a red curve,
and a while ago
there was an area between where the
two buildings were. There was a... well,
commentator, your time is up, but
if you want to wait over there  Or back, we
have to move forward with the
next commentator. Before the
next commentator,
call Sanderson,
Mike Water,
Anders,
and Palomustos.
Good morning. What topics?
General public comment. I'll take a
minute.
Good morning, all council members.
I'm Edgar Resines, and I'm a
fast-food worker. I've been working in
the fast-food industry for a few
years, and I'm here to ask for your
support for
the
Fast Food Justice Ordinance, which will benefit
many fast-food workers,
many like me, who need
paid vacations, fair hours,
and to know their rights. Thank you for
listening, have a good day, and God
bless you all.
Commentator, what topics would you like to
discuss?
Good morning, City Council. What topics would you like to
discuss? I'd like to
make a public comment about the
Fast Food Ordinance.
I'm Cesar Lopez. I'm a member of the
Fast Food Workers Union. I worked for
five years at Swe and worked various shifts
without pay, up to 12 hours a week. I wasn't
given breaks and lived paycheck to
paycheck. I accumulated  $1,000 in
credit card debt. I'm trying to
survive. I didn't know I had the right
to pay for those lost hours and breaks
. I thought if I didn't finish
my duties on time, I had to
work,
and now I know that's illegal. I demand that they
pay me what they owe me.
Many fast-food workers
still suffer, which they don't
know about, and the
Los Angeles Workers Council can help them learn their
rights.
Workers need laws to
protect consumers, businesses, and
employees as well.
Thank you very much. Next commentator.
Good morning. What topics would you like to
discuss? General comment. Thank you. This is
Paloma Bustos, an
association
member with Chinivalcu.
They are expecting the World Cup and the
Olympic Games to bring $1 billion
in economic activity, but
also pressure to build
and increased costs for
workers, hospitality, and
events. We know from past Olympics
and World Cups that when there is
pressure to work quickly, the risk
of exploitation increases for immigrants.
In fact, forced labor has been identified
in connection with every Olympic Games and
World Cup.  In the past decade,
a report came out that there are clear steps
the city can take to
enforce these laws, to ensure they
have the services to prevent
harm before it happens. Let's be
prepared to share that report with
you so that
global celebrations don't come at the cost of
dignity.
Next commentator. Uh, well, with
the microphone,
wireless microphone.
I'm a U.S. veteran.
I live at 15 105 Sharman Way
in B5,
and between
09, 5049,
and 105,
there's a walkway that needs to be painted either
red or blue or both
because there are cars parked there
blocking it for disabled people,
preventing them from using the street, and that
's unacceptable.
Someone here told me it's going to
take 25 years to get it done. That's not
acceptable to me either.
I want it done yesterday.
I want blue lines so that
people who park there get a
ticket
because the way it is now, we call
for someone to come and give a ticket, and they don't come.
A fine because there is no
indication.
Commentator, your time is up. If you
could wait back there
for a moment. Thank you.
Good morning. What topics would you like to
comment on? Good morning, sir. I want to
make a general comment.
I have a subject that affects us
all. One minute forward.
I am Frederick Williams.
I say that I am a
civilized American.
We have an international crisis, a
situation that is affecting us
all. Businesses are closing here
in Los Angeles, I see that. So,
unemployment is certainly increasing.
The number of 1,000 millionaires has
grown
in dollar terms for those
millionaires, 1,000 millionaires has
increased, and this
is a simple formula. If you consider
this,
we simply have a national and
international crisis. We need a
tax overhaul, the situation
where others
pay nothing and those millionaires...
Your time is up.
Next speaker. Before the next
commentator, I'm going to call Brandon
Audit, David Plum, Richard, Gloria,
Terra de León, Michel Sheffron, and Nick
Holden.
Good morning. What topics would you like to
talk about? General comments and the two
related to the raids of  ICE,
public comment, and the two
related to the raids. Two
minutes for topics 29 and 30 if you can
start with those two and then
general public comment.
I'm Eric, a photographer helping to
document our response since
June. I want to thank Councilwoman
Rodriguez as she marked the beginning of the year,
saying we are ready to fight. I hope she's
right because I need her
help. I think a lot in visual metaphor,
thinking with 100
community members walking from Mariachi Plaza
to the detention center in remembrance of
René Good, Keith Porter, and all the
victims of this regime, and Councilwoman
plus five. The people dying in
the conditions of
AC's detention centers also deserve to be
remembered. Visual metaphor. A moment
walking, crossing the bridge over the
Los Angeles River, surrounded by
industrial disasters and a vigil for a woman
who died. It
was windy and cold, and it was dark
because the lights are all off
because people are stealing electricity,
taking cables to survive. We've now passed
the point.
The moment has arrived.
You have to back up your
words with passion. The gentleman who
spoke about Kid Porter's family is
right. This is going to be very difficult, but
now is the time. There's no more
waiting. I'm glad you
started the hearing this way because a
moment ago I had a different
visual metaphor. I know that...  Everyone needs to
say it, but I want to point out that
the meeting literally began with
pledging
allegiance to the flag, which was one of the
demonstrations.
If they can't do anything to get rid of
ISO, the police need to tell us
why.  Go to the public and do something
different.  Now is the time to
secure, we have to ensure that
we have more after this.  Thank you.
Good morning.  Which points would you like
to discuss?  Good morning.  This is a
general public comment.  I would like to say
good morning to
Councillor Hernandez, Jury.
Now,
the issue I
need support on is
specifically about the
sworn councilor.  I live in the east of the city,
uh, Dylan is great,
but so is Tokyo.  But the problems we
Skyro residents see—I'm a
Marxist,
I'm very Marxist—
and
the way we've interacted with
the local government has been very effective.   We
need to develop a method that is
more in line with what we know
is right in terms of what
we can achieve, or what can be achieved
with intentions.  Uh, I just
want to say hello to Isabel Jurado.  It is
an honor to be a resident of your
district.  That's all.
Good afternoon.  What points would
you like to discuss?  Points related to
ICE and general commentary.  So you have
2 minutes for each point and one minute
for general comment.  In light of the
murder of Ren Good and the two people
who were shot last night, I think
of my grandfather who fought against
fascism across the sea.  We don't have
time for nice words.  We need
action.  We need the strength to
address these problems, because our
fundamental freedoms are
threatened
these days.  Hey, the day has come,
we need action, we need passion,
we need creativity, we need
people to rise up and at least if we're going
to fall, we're going to fall fighting.   I
can admit, even I am afraid and I
imagine many of you are
too, but we need
leadership, we need resolve
because I saw the video of that woman
who was shot in the face.   I
never thought I would see this in
my own country.  When I heard about the
Bastos in Portland, I got scared because I
had to call my friends to
make sure they were okay.
The problem is horrifying.
Like I said, we don't need words,
we need action, we need a plan.
What the hell are they going to do?  I say,
"I loved your words, Mrs.
Rodriguez, but what are you going to do, how are you
going to keep us safe, how are you going to
prevent people from being
murdered
at the hands of federal agents?"  Thank you.
Next speaker.
Good afternoon.  What points would
you like to discuss?
I want to talk about points
29, 12, and 30. And I'd like to make a
general comment as well,
ma'am, please wait.
Point number two is not open for
public comment, but you can
talk about the others.
I want to talk about how I support the
federal government, I support President Donald
Trump, I support what they are doing to
remove these illegal people from
this country.  When
these illegal immigrants are brought back to our
country, it creates opportunities for
Americans.  I also want to talk about
the situation where he had to
protect himself.  I'm talking about people,
women and men, who put on
uniforms and protect people who don't
belong here.
There are people who want to receive services
for free and instead of
supporting our officers, we
want to punish them.
If you have the...
if you could put on this
uniform knowing that you might not be able to
return to your families, you can call me
crazy, but something my great-grandmother always
taught me is that you have to have, you have to
be honest because the problem is not
Derek Bling Game, the problem is the
system we have created.
The other point I want to
talk about is point 29.
Regarding the demonstrators, how
dare this government collaborate and
prevent people from going out into
the streets?  How dare they?  In my
last 20 seconds regarding these
points, I also want to bring attention to
the
Los Angeles Police Department. While we're
talking about the police force, they are
criminals. They
have acted indecently. They are not
a professional agency. They have
not provided me with
records that I have requested, including
crime reports and
body camera footage.
I had to go and ask for these
reports.
Let me tell you, I have weighed
500 pounds, 400 pounds.
I fought with the
municipal prosecutor, that [ __ ].
If they think I'm going to back down and not
fight, they should call Georgia
and find out how I fought and won.
Sir, your time is up.  Sir, your
time is up.  This concludes.
This is your final warning.
Thank you, prosecutor.
Sir, this is your first and last warning,
Miss Secretary.  Mr. President,
the Council may now
vote on points 1, 22, 25 to 27
and also 31.
These points are in front of us.
We're going to open the list, close the list,
and tabulate the votes.
14 in favor.  Next, it
continues with point number two, and that was
called a
special motion by Hernández Yoscar.
Let's open the list.  Close the list
of votes.  14 in favor.
Next,
next.
Points 23 and 24 were
called as a separate vote by
councilors Jurado and Hernández.  Okay.  23
and 24
named as special by councilor
Jurado Hernández.  For separate votes
we will open the list.  Close the list.
To collect the votes.
10 in favor and four against.  What's
next?
Point 23 follows, named especially by
Mr. Soto Martínez also as
councilor Ramel.  I think that's point
29, sorry.  Yes, 29. Correct, Councilor
Soto Martínez.  Yes, thanks.  Hey, Mr.
President, in Spanish there's a saying that
goes, "Only the people can save the people."
And this, this is what it's all about.  This notion
means that only the people can
save the nation.  If we talk about
the demonstrations that are happening
through the angels, I think we can
all agree that we can
improve this motion.  uh call a
formal policy uh so we can collaborate
with demonstrations uh to plan for
security and manage expectations.
Many of us can name
examples or
how we have seen these
distinct elements.  For me, a
very clear example is the demonstration that happened
after David Huerta, the president
of Cayu.  Uh, in June I attended this
march uh led by uh Labor in
Grand Park and I noticed that I did
n't notice that there were so uh few officers
uh at this uh
this demonstration.
This is because there was collaboration and
communication structures,
and I want to be very clear, it's not about
asking for permission to march, it's just
to be very clear
and develop a way to communicate
with departments like LPD.  This
helps to avoid the need for
intervention, police intervention.
I really appreciate that the boss has come
here to have a dialogue about how to
address this.
When we have clear communication
we can control the situation and
keep everyone safe.  We see fewer
confrontations and fewer people
injured for
these purposes.  I also call
upon the angels who collaborate with them, like those in
New York and Boston.  Under this model,
these officers are
only
nearby and are only
called when they are really
needed.  So in my opinion,
I think that the
police officers are being put into these
demonstrations prematurely.
I want to thank the
department, the
police commission, and my colleagues on the
public safety committee for their support of this
motion.  I do believe that if we adopt this,
we can limit our
responsibility.   I
respectfully ask you to vote
in favor.
Okay.  We have other speakers on this
point.  I have a councilor.
Thank you.  I just want to get up and
thank Councillor Soto
Martinez for bringing this motion forward.
Within these cameras, I believe
we have documented the violence that we have
seen
since they have really terrorized
communities here in Los Angeles, but I
think our courage is also
based on the fact that we are different, we
are not using our powers
as police officers to terrorize
people.
But what I have seen
is a lot of testimony and recordings where
police officers have been
balanced
and demonstrative, feeling
scared and confused.
And our structure
allows that
by design
our city is designed this
way and just looking at the agenda which is the
police commission, they have not
fit in, they have not addressed these
problems.  Um,
I really think it's important that we do this
, that we treat this
differently,
that we face this
differently, that we think about it differently
.  We are expecting demonstrations
tomorrow.  How are we going to
look at this?
When motions are brought into
this chamber, it sometimes takes
years for action to be taken.
I hope that the public safety committee
, the mayor's office
that manages these
offices, will take action
quickly and that we will see
effective changes.  So thank you, Mr. Soto
Martínez.  And I hope we can see some
real action.
Thank you, Councilor Rodriguez.  Thank you
Councillor Soto Martinez for this motion and
for starting these conversations.  I
want to thank Mr. Lee for
allowing us to move this forward regarding
public safety.  I just want
to remind everyone and each person
when we have problems
related to public safety or
reforms
or the organic charter or about
conversations about the problems of
homeless people.  It is important
that when we schedule events on the agenda, we
consider which
departments are actually active.
So when you're sitting here
inside these motions
and obstructing these conversations,
you're obstructing.   I
just want to make it very clear when
conversations are hindered and
policies aren't moving forward
because there's this, I don't know, fear,
inhibition, resistance
to actually effect change.
So let's either
have an opportunity to
have a comprehensive conversation
regarding the spending of funds for the
homelessness problem
within the charter that is currently
having discussions about what
the structure
of this city is really going to look like.
There are obstructions to these motions
currently, so I'm glad
this emotion is here.  But you know
what, folks, there's a reason the
public is so angry, they have every
right to be, but make no
mistake.
The silence
that allows, as a leadership of
this council,
the lack of programming so that
we can effect change are in
collaboration.  So I hope this
year truly marks a year of change.
When these conversations happen, and of course,
we can have different opinions
about them, but not
having them is a
leadership failure. So I really hope this
marks a change for you, not just in this
specific problem, but in several
where there has been a failure,
an obstacle in having these
conversations, and the public has every
right to be so angry.
Ah, we've had plenty of time to
hold these meetings and advance
these motions in their
respective committees, but enough with the
delays and excuses.   We
all need to understand the role
we swore to serve, but
to avoid taking action, that has to
stop.  I hope this stops in the
new year, so I
hope these kinds of conversations
will be the model for the conversations
we start having so that the public can
clearly see where we stand.
Very good.  Well, Councillor Mac, yes,
I want to say briefly, speaking of this
motion, thank you Councillor for moving
this motion forward.   It happens to me when I'm
talking to the public,
working with the
police department, with us to create better
public safety, talking about the
port peace patrol or
interventionists in my district.  I
often quote someone and almost never
give them credit, but I said that a very
wise man told me there is no way
to take the public out of
public safety.  And I wanted to say it in front of him, there is no
reason to bring the
public out of
public safety.  Thank you, Mr. Soto
Martínez.  We can hold the vote.  14
in favor.  Very good.  What else?  Next up
we have topic number 30,
called special by Councilor
Hernández for comments.
Councilor Hernández.  Thank you, Mr.
President.
Crossing into the United States, seeing
an erosion of
confidence in migration enforcement.
Hundreds of masked and
anonymous agents are operating without the
transparency and accountability that
our democracy demands.  Defending
the right to remain without
masks.  The Trump administration
is giving tools to every
kidnapper and extortionist.  to
impress the execution and the
authorities.
This allows people who can
dress up as civilians to terrorize
citizens.  Mothers in San Pedro and San
Pico Union, how can you tell the difference
between a real officer and someone
pretending to be one when neither of them
shows their badge or ID?
People are demanding that people
take action now.  This motion before you asks that
the municipal prosecutor identify every
possible modification.  for the
Municipal Code to maximize penalties for
people pretending to be authorities and
also asks that every person arrested
can demand
verifiable identification and authority.  Thanks to
Councillor Blomenfield for co-introducing and
supporting it, and to the committees on
civil rights and equity, immigration and
public safety
for promoting it.
This is not a license to terrorize,
and the council should make that stronger and
clearer.  Colleagues, let's use every
tool we can to hold
agents accountable, including those posing as
agents.  Let's do everything we
can to protect the
civil and constitutional rights
of these people committing these
crimes.
I ask for support for this motion.  Thank you,
Councilor Hernández.  The vote on
this issue.  14 in favor.
Now, what else?  The council has
motions to publish and refer.  They are
published and referenced.  However,
I think you had
No, no, no.  For item number two that
was approved, I mean,
item number two makes what we often
do in our district, whether it's a
sanitation garden,
police or fire division, or an
animal shelter, we go, we visit, we look
at the operations, and we respond to
constituents by doing the work to
work with the mayor's office,
the commission
being the one that's carrying that out.  In
this case, visiting the
animal shelter, they discovered that there are
restrictions on council members not being allowed to
pass through portions of the
animal shelter.
In the United States, it is difficult for a
member of Congress to be in an
outreach center.  On one side, it's an
animal shelter, which is not a
good thing.  We are submitting a motion to
understand the rules regarding
animal services.
A written rule was reinstated, and
today's amendments were to state
where this comes from, what authority
you have, and how we can create
policies so that council members can
visit an animal shelter
without making an appointment 48 hours in
advance and be told upon
arrival that we cannot enter.
So, thank you for passing that
motion.  You are waiting to return
because, like a fire station, police
station, or sanitation center, we should be
able to enter an
animal shelter and see the
operations.  Thank you, Mr. McOS.
The motions and announcements were published and referred to,
Councilor Roman.  Yes, on a
slightly less serious note,
we received a notification from the
Griffith Observatory, sharing
that Dr. CRP,
longtime director, was awarded the
education prize by the American Astronomical Society
, an organization of
professional astronomers. It
is one of the biggest awards at that
site
and encourages
making the cosmos more inspiring for
everyone.  We were able to honor the 90th anniversary
here in the chamber last year with
Dr. CR and he spoke beautifully as he
always does.  His enthusiasm and love
for the stars is evident in everything he
does, and we wish him
very warm congratulations.  We are
grateful to have him as a
city employee at
Griffith Observatory.  Thank you.  Now, Councilor
Mcosker, before we make the
requests,
I have an announcement, colleagues, this
week we celebrate Three Kings Day,
a celebration in several districts.
In district 15 we celebrated it as
you did, this tradition
with sweet cakes and dolls inside
the rosca.   I
went to Wilmington Without Borders SBCC
wearing cute sneakers
for the Three Kings Day celebration.
A tremendous success
with toys, food, and entertainment.
The Wilmington community has not
done so yet, although on January 6th he came and
went.  He wants to invite everyone to
join him for the first-ever Three
Kings Day celebration on the
Wilmington promenade.
We'll have food provided by In and
Out,
live camels, and a boat tour.  The first
500 families will receive a rosca.
I hope to see you there tomorrow at the
water border.  I want to thank all the
sponsors
for activating the Wilmington promenade in
this way, having a
great forecast, adding this menida in the
water.  Okay, I'm going to ask everyone to
stand for
the motions to adjourn the session.  To
my left
and to my right is Councillor Rodríguez.
Thank you.  Well, colleagues, I stand up
to adjourn the session in memory
of Akil B,
a visionary leader,
one of the most respected voices in
community violence intervention who
passed away over four decades ago.
Dr. Bachir dedicated his life to
breaking cycles of violence, creating
safer and stronger communities.
Menu spoke of his years in Los Angeles,
growing up in an environment where
survival and dignity were often
denied, and how those experiences shaped his
vision to bring structure, discipline, and
peace where there was often much chaos.
Cober
founded
Build and then established the Institute
for Training and Innovation.
Through these organizations, he trained
and certified several interventionists,
men and women on the front
lines, in neighborhoods, de-escalating
conflicts, saving lives, and
turning despair into leadership.   It was
based on the belief that the
closer they are to the pain, the closer they are to
the solution.  He understood that addressing
violence requires more than just policing; it
requires empowering communities
with credibility and restoring trust
from within.  Dr. Blir's influence
extended far beyond Los Angeles.  Their models
were adopted in countries all over the world,
from South America to Africa and Asia.
Hood alerted national and international agencies and offered a guide
for working with minors involved
with gangs.  He received several awards,
the California Peace Prize and a
doctorate for his
global contributions to building peace, but he
remained humble, often saying,
"Don't judge the possibilities by what
can be based on the circumstances."
In the end, Dr. Bier stood like a
teacher and a mirror to the city, reminding us
that
public safety cannot exist without trust and
that true peace is not implemented, it is
built.
His death was a great tragedy to the
communities he served and the peace he
worked to find and to all the
Angelenos who benefited
from his commitment to peace, respect and love.
Today we honor his legacy, his leadership, and
his belief
and commitment to the people.
Dr. Berir, physician.  I am here with so many
PCI members
who have been instrumental in
training
during COVID.   I
secured
approximately one
and a half million dollars to ensure
ongoing training for interventionists in the city,
because what we need is the
ability to give people the
tools to be effective in their
tasks.
They
worked and did their jobs.
National examples were made
of how to train interventionists and
give people the tools to
deal with the traumas that were
occurring throughout the city.
That was important work.   They
cannot give these rules to individuals
without the tools to be
effective and consistent
in the city.
We lost a true hero and a
dear friend.   It's
very difficult to do this work, to be in
our communities, to help
prevent the violence that would continue to
happen if it weren't for the work of
many people, and many people
greatly support the worker, the people
intervening
there in the streets doing this
important work.
For our work, it's about ensuring
they have the
tools to be effective and not turning their
backs when resources aren't being
provided to them, and doing it
correctly.  So, colleagues, I want to
take this moment to say that I am
grateful
for all the work and friendships and
lessons I learned from Kill
and so many text messages with
affirmations of when I took
hard positions that often
caused me a lot of criticism from
people there in the hall.   It was about
doing the right thing.   He
was a man who wanted to do the
right thing and he set that example with
all his heart.  And there are people who work
much better now and with more confidence
because of the examples of his leadership, and for
that I am very grateful, and I know that his
work and his legacy will continue
in the individuals who did this
work alongside him.  I am very
grateful to all of you who
worked on this
Centorians building.
I remember Aquila telling me, I do
n't know how
the president of public safety is
here in these meetings going to Jersey
looking at all the models of how we
can do it right and better.  These
are the individuals who are
helping to drive that change, how to
do it better, and I hope that in their
memory we can continue to
have that commitment, ensuring that
we can do it better and well and that we do not
take
any shortcuts, and may they rest in peace and
power.
Thank you very much, Councilor Rodriguez, and
thanks to the community
and friends of Aquil, one of our
most famous warriors
for peace.
Just this week we received the news
that Los Angeles has had fewer
homicides this year than at any
time since 1965.
And
the majority of them were
gang-related homicides.  And that is the
greatest testimony, that when He
started this work we had almost more
than 1000 homicides per year.  Well, it
started
and there is a lot of credit, but you can't
ignore the contributions of Aquil and
with your permission, Rodriguez, if you can
add me to this
motion and Mr. Price, I as
well.
All members signed, all
members for this topic.  Thank you
all very much.  I will make a motion to adjourn the
session.  Well, that adjourns the
session.  Thank you all very much.
fa and see how grateful they are.  It is
an amazing thing.
The volunteers are from the community.
Many of them are my family members.
Everybody's here to give up a hand.  My
whole team has been out here since early
this morning organizing
food is really expensive and people have
food insecurities.
This should stabilize how they feel
about what their next meal is.  And that's what
we're trying to satisfy.
Two sides of the same coin are at work
in South LA with funding for green and
sustainable projects.  Parks in the area
getting EV chargers and more tree
coverage, both of which will help bring
down pollution levels in the
neighborhoods.
We Harbor Park in South Alb
facilities of the South Ecol for the
EV Chargers.
This is part of a bigger program,
universal basic mobility which is a 30
million investment in South Los Angeles
to bring mobility options, access to
opportunity and increase transportation
equity while reducing greenhouse gas
emissions at the same time.
The bureau guns uh invited to
participate in the TCC grant program and
our role is to install 16 EV chargers
across four different parks here in
South LA.  Our charging program is a
little different than most.  Um we
installed chargers on existing
infrastructure.  Uh we found that our
existing streetlight circuits had extra
capacity when we converted to LEDs.  We
currently have over 800 chargers
throughout the city of Los Angeles.
So these chargers are going to offer a
convenient place for people to charge
close to home, especially for people who
may have challenges charging at home,
like people who live in multi-family
housing.
So I we're working with community
organizations such as three people to
increase the community canopy in South
Alm
canopy expansion project and its main
goal is to advance shade and tree equity
by planting 4,000 trees and city
parkways and also distributing 2,000
fruit or shade trees to residents to
plant in their home.
Both projects will help each other.  The
charging station will help uh with
pollution with less uh carbon monoxide
and in the area and uh the tree planning
will help absorb that uh carbon monoxide
with the events that we had in certain
parks where we gave away free seeds and
like he said with the trees we were also
teaching you how to plant and provide
and take care of the tree.
This is the first park that we're
completing the installations.  Uh we are
working uh in different parks in South
where we are also installing EV
chargers.  Our next park will be Bermont
Square, South Park and the wetlands.
LA sanitation takes in hazardous
household waste at its safe centers.  The
LAWP is hosting a customer service
Saturday on January 17th and volunteer
signups are open for the 2026 Greater
Los Angeles homeless count.  These
stories up next on City Beat.
LA Sanitation wants to let Angelinos
know that its safe centers are permanent
collection sites for hazardous household
and electronic waste.  Safe stands for
solvents, automotive, flammables, and
electronics.  And the safe centers take
in items such as aerosol cans,
batteries, paints, and more.  LA City
Sanitation advises keeping items in
their original containers if possible
and placing waste securely in the trunk
separate from personal belongings.
Residents are allowed 15 gallons or up
to 125 lb per vehicle per visit to the
center.  For more information, visit Safe
Center under new battery collection
centers at the website
sanitation.lacity.gov.
the Los Angeles Department of Water.