so
it's i almost
can't believe it how far i've come
compared to where i was the first day
and now as part of the lapd family these
officers will protect and serve us all
want to buy some art well la's the place
to be gil reyes takes us to the city's
biggest art show of the year
the la convention center home to the e3
gaming expo the la auto show and so many
other events hosted the la art show for
its 24th year executive director
cassandra voyages told us why it's
unlike any other art show on the planet
the beauty of this show is that you can
visit
so many galleries in one space
and so many different types of artwork
when the la art show first got started
back in 1994 there were just 14
galleries and 250 attendees now it has
grown to over 130 galleries and art
institutions with tens of thousands of
people attending timothy yarger a
beverly hills gallery owner showed us
this original david hockney valued at
350 thousand dollars
and don't adjust your television sets
these are artists mads christensen's
light works made with energy efficient
leds a hot seller at 32 000 dollars a
pop
part of the reason that mads christensen
has touched collectors and buyers so
deeply
is that
unlike a static work of art that's in
your home you might enjoy it but these
change constantly
so the emotional and visual experience
has a lot of stamina
the other thing that's important it's
not on a loop
it never repeats itself like cars well
they had cars too an lapd black and
white but actually just half of one
there was art from all over the world
and closer to home from art share la
based in downtown's arts district the
space nurtures up and coming artists
we focus on giving artists access and we
really kind of want to stay ingrained in
the downtown community so we thought sc
mera would be the perfect artist to
bring here sc mero a skid row artist
made this piece with 6
600 pennies
a lot of my work is about the
transmutation or transformation
of materials but the underlying message
is about the transformation of the
individual souls which will no doubt be
inspired at every colorful corner of the
la art show
folks at the la art show say prices for
individual works range between 6 000 to
a million dollars
i'll take two please
and they were off hundreds of runners
turned out for the half marathon and 5k
run through iconic griffith park grab
your running shoes and see if you can
keep up with our own councilmember david
rue
say
good morning i am proud to be here on
the world famous the largest urban park
in the nation griffith park to host the
fifth annual griffith park run we're
really happy to put on this event every
year the la parks foundation raises
money for our city parks all 450 of los
angeles city parks
[Music]
you came here to create the park today
had a great day i had a fantastic day
for the 5k
and what a beautiful day with so many
thousands of people running
i think it's great it gets
people out to the different parks
or involved i love it i used to do the
half marathon a little bit tough on my
legs causes on the road but the 5k is
just enough
beautiful place beautiful weather and
awesome people so i'm really happy to
take part here
[Music]
over at dodger stadium dodger mania was
at a fever pitch as fans don their
favorite blues for the seventh annual
dodgers fan fest check it out
[Music]
we're here at dodgers fanfest
it's a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity to
lay down in the field that the dodgers
play on my community would come to see
my team
as a super fan i have fun with it i've
been doing this since 2012.
[Music]
it's going to be a great year
it's awesome to see
that as much as we give and we love the
dodgers they give back so i was standing
over there and justin turner came up and
i touched my hand and i'm never washing
his hand because justin turner touched
it
[Music]
this next story can't get any cuter a
newborn at the la zoo is getting lots of
attention but he's growing fast so you
better hurry
[Music]
so we had our poodle fawn born here at
the los angeles zoo he's out on exhibit
for everyone to see with his mom and dad
he is still pretty small and he has the
spots um and at about three months old
he is going to be full grown this is the
first time in a while we've had an
exhibit of pudu um so we're really
excited for guests to be able to see
them so when we announced on social
media it was just going to be you know
here's a really cute baby animal that
you can enjoy started to see responses
on social media from people saying oh
looks just like hitch on oh that's that
poodle should be named hichon and we
were all like what's that who is that
started to look into it and fans of the
k-pop group encity have already said
that the singer hechon resembles a pudu
so our baby poodoo is now named hechon
and you can visit him at the la zoo with
his parents stephen mario
and
he'll be he'll be full size grown up
pretty soon so if you want to see him
with his spots looking like an adorable
little fawn you should come soon
good news when it comes to crime in our
city the mayor puts his presidential bid
to rest and a new program helps put more
boots on the ground to keep
neighborhoods safe all this in city beat
the two things i love the most
my family and my city are right here in
la
so i've decided not to throw my hat into
the ring to run for president in 2020.
ending months of speculation la mayor
eric garcetti has chosen not to seek the
democratic nomination for president
indicating he'll stay right here and
continue to helm la's continuing
advances in technology economics and
humanitarian issues
to that the mayor announced that major
crime in los angeles has dropped
significantly since last year these
decreases directly correlate to the
mayor's initiative in getting more
officers out from behind desks and back
on the street
councilwoman nuri martinez announced a
new volunteer community patrol program
at lapd mission division the program is
designed to support ongoing lapd efforts
in the valley i'm going to ride along
with one of the teams that we're going
to go look for stolen vehicles these
community members are all volunteers
leaders in their neighborhoods so they
know every square inch of these
neighborhoods in this community and
they're the extra eyes and ears for the
police department
[Music]
from one-of-a-kind jewelry paintings and
arts and crafts the ecla art walk
highlights the work of local talent and
delivers quite a block party
[Music]
easily artwork it's a community
organized event it's been happening for
five years at the corner of first
student indiana and it happens on the
second sunday of each month rain
shine
or
lightning
[Applause]
[Music]
we came up with the idea of the artwork
we wanted
for something to be educational and
beautifying for the community at the
same time that it brought additional
food traffic for the local businesses we
bring a vibe to the community every
second sunday and i know it's
appreciated because we always have a
dance floor in front of my booth we try
to bring a diverse
a diverse pool of entertainment we have
local vendors local designers we have
painters local crafters that live within
two mile radius is the label height
commerce area who come and partake of
the event
the local community gets to appreciate
the art
[Music]
we do a silk screening workshop as well
with poltevarte studios it allows the
community to come and actually learn how
to print as well as create their own
stencils so they can make their own art
and kind of hopefully spark the next
generation to be young artists and
entrepreneurs as well it's free for the
public it's family friendly pet friendly
adjective uia friendly we are making
sure that we
are catering to all of these subcultures
within our community we're trying to
create a thriving economy for artists
and entrepreneurs to exist we're trying
to create more business and more wealth
in our communities of color everybody
should at least experience it one time
and find out for themselves how awesome
it is
but if unique food is more your thing
check out smorgasburg la it's got
everything you can think of from lobster
whole fried fish cuban sandwiches and
ice cream all of my favorites it's la's
top destination for every taste hope
you're hungry
zach
brooks i'm the general manager of
smorgasburg la
[Music]
well the event is based on like food
they have all different types of vendors
people who have different little shops
so
definitely something that's fun to come
to on sundays
so smorgansburg is actually a new york
company it started in new york where we
run a bunch of different markets
it opened in la two and a half years ago
but it's not a new york market plop down
in l.a it's actually a la market all the
vendors are are from here in l.a well
honestly this is the first time here
we're driving all the way from a
riverside and everything looks pretty
nice there's a lot of variety and
diversity around there's a lot of
different foods you could try out
definitely a lot of delicious food
well i mean it's some of the best food
in los angeles i have my friends here
with me from out of town they're from
west virginia and i just wanted them to
have a very good experience there's
pretty much something for everybody here
you can find every kind of food
imaginable we have some of the best
mexican food in l.a from seafood to
vegan to cuban puerto rican they have
food vendors they have ice cream vendors
they have beer vendors we have middle
eastern food asian food barbecue we want
to try the lobster down there
[Music]
you're 100 free to get in every single
sunday from 10 to 4 and we have a huge
parking lot that is free for two hours
don't eat breakfast so with reference we
come before you come here
smorgasburg lay happens every sunday so
grab your bib in stretchy pants and
visit la.smorgasburg.com
a new music series is about to take
center stage help connect those
experiencing homelessness with service
providers and celebrate black history
month during a pan-african film and art
festival all this and things to do
explore music ideas and the spoken word
through compose la an ambitious music
presentation and companion lecture
series happening in storied music venues
throughout los angeles in this inaugural
workshop clock shop la will host a
symposium entitled nicole mitchell's
spiderweb don't miss compose la
beginning saturday february 9th at 7 30
p.m
clock shop la is located at 2806
clearwater street for more information
visit clockshop.org
[Music]
the last fellas connect day event is
looking for a few good volunteers the
goal is to connect people experiencing
homelessness with employment counselors
health professionals and other service
providers lend your helping hand to the
los feliz connect day happening saturday
february 12 from 10 a.m to 2 p.m at the
friendship auditorium to volunteer for
the event email
cd4.issues lacity.org
head on down to the baldwin hills
crenshaw plaza for the 27th annual
pan-african film and arts festival the
festival features over 170 new black
films from around the world and exhibits
from over 100 fine artists and unique
craftspeople
treat yourself to the pan-african film
and arts festival happening february 7th
through the 18th at the cinemark rave 15
theaters at baldwin hills crenshaw plaza
for details visit paff.org
and that's a look at some things to do
[Music]
that's it for this edition i'm um
rasheed from all of us here at la this
week thank you for joining us a reminder
that you can catch us online at
lacityview.org
we're also on facebook twitter and
youtube see you next time for more la
this week
[Music]
do
need a recycling center
call 311 the toll-free number for
non-emergency services 3-1-1 you're one
call the city hall
hi i'm kevin from chatsworth offering
you a taste of new orleans since 1986.
you're watching la city view channel 35
our city our channel
[Music]
so
do
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
do
[Music]
foreign
do
[Music]
hello
uh
[Music]
oh
so
[Music]
do
so
[Music]
do
so
[Music]
good morning good morning if everyone
would please take their seats
if everyone would please take their
seats
today is wednesday february 13th
welcome to city hall this council meets
every tuesday wednesday and friday at 10
the public is welcome we have a quorum
adam clerk what you call a roll
blumenfell bonnen buscano sedillo
harristassen wieser caretzkorian
martinez of farrell price rodriguez rue
smith wesson 13 members and a quorum mr
president thank you very much
continue
approval of the minutes uh o'farrow
moves bonn in seconds next
commendatory resolutions for approval
wizard moves rue seconds that brings us
where
mr president items one through twelve
are items for which public hearings have
been held the economic development
committee reports for items six and
twelve have been submitted posted and
circulated all right let's prepare to
vote on those items
open the roll
close the row
tabulate the vote thirteen eyes continue
and mr president there is a request to
send item 6 forth with
so order
and then items 13 and 14 are items
scheduled for closed session public
hearings have been held for those items
would you like to hold those on the desk
why don't we for a moment let's do that
and that brings us
mr president that then takes us back to
presentations or general public comment
so i want to quickly call up dory frank
dory frank please come forward
followed by mr previn
let me grab this real quick
yes sir i'm here representing hatsala
which is the emergency
system both in pico fairfax north
hollywood councilman corats
um kokori and know about it and there's
been a big fight between the la fighters
union and hudson regarding running
ambulances in
those three i do know that hudson
arrives within two minutes of a person
calling i'm asking that
hatsol should be brought on the agenda
for the city council determined finally
after 18 years we're not the city
council approve of hudsula dr having
three ambulances in the area to help
people
save their lives
that's why i called about and paul knows
about this mr raoul knows about this and
mr kokori knows about it so i'd like to
put on the agenda so hotel can come into
the city council have the firemen junior
come in and explain why they're not
allowed to run ambulances yes time is of
the essence and that's why i'm here to
talk about it
i would like today that you put that
somehow put it on the agenda thank you
sir mr president
mr president yes no mr president not you
mr sorry
yes sir
don't you call my items
no you only have a general public
comment give them just one minute go
ahead oh okay can you give me back oh
thank you okay yeah well i guess so none
of the items are available for speaking
there's some really interesting stuff
down in the port the airport all these
kind of interesting new jobs for the
controller i don't know i feel like we
should be able to speak on those since
they're on the legislative bodies agenda
and now we shouldn't oh why because you
were heard in committee
yeah they weren't and by the way um
there's no agendas in the room once
again civil rights leaders mr harris
dawson didn't see you yesterday with the
thousands of people roaring against the
big incarcerator for the mentally
challenge you know mental health people
so what we would like to do is get
public meeting agendas right here in the
room i think you were here the other day
when sean murphy one of our uh
constituents came down and could not
find a public meeting agenda he was
directed he got upset with the clerk
it's not cool sir i know you're a civil
rights leader and a hero to many people
but you have to provide i think even
kakorian who's not here today and rue
would would agree and i just want to
make one comment monica rodriguez
holding a 3 p.m public safety meeting
with about 35 items all of which include
you know 2.5 million thank you mr
president thank you sir
and agendas can be picked up at the
clerk's office and
we have an electronic agenda just for
those that are watching in the back of
the room all right that
closes general public comment
um
madam
clerk and adam city attorney for the day
i'd now like to
recognize mr blumenfield are you ready
for your presentation then the floor is
yours
everybody up here
mr president colleagues today we are
here to recognize and bring awareness to
social media safety
social media can be used to build
communities spread information across
the world help advance the missions of
non-governmental organizations give
historical disadvantages communities and
accessible
an accessibility platform we know all of
the wonderful benefits of social media
however
the ubiquity of social media access also
changes how bad actors and criminals can
prey on society
notably foster youth domestic violence
survivors
marginalized communities
we've seen a lot of dangers with social
media as well
late last year one of my team members
cameron who's over there
attended the annual peace and kindness
walk in the western san fernando valley
the walk is one of the many actions our
community has taken to rally together
and to stand up and spread the message
of anti-bullying and kindness
the walk also recognizes how one local
high school teenager went to el camino
goes to el camino jordan pisner was
viciously attacked by two teenagers for
the sake of internet fame and safety
jordan which is he's right back here
he was cold cocked
knocked out
all because somebody wanted to show it
on video
it took him years but he is now
skateboarding again he's a good kid
um and he is a testament into turning
adversity into
advocacy now
we need to take
innovation actions on our part as a city
and we need to do things to recognize
social media safety
unfortunately a lot of people don't
realize about
cyber crimes that are out there and
about some of the dangers with social
media
cyber criminals are targeting everyone
from youth to seniors
so the first step that we can do is
bring awareness to the problem i'm glad
that by declaring today which is what
we're going to do social media safety
day millions will become aware and
empowered to protect themselves their
loved ones and the community
and i'm glad to be joined by the
organization for social media safety
this is a group that's based in the west
san fernando valley it is the nation's
first non-profit that serves as a
consumer protection organization focused
solely on social media safety
through innovative educational programs
legislative advocacy technology
development
they are right by our side
in contenting which is still the the
wild digital west that we have
so our first guest speaker i want to
introduce is mark bergman
he's the executive director for the
organization of social media he has a
long history advocating for marginalized
groups at the national and state level
and he was instrument instrumental in
creating jordan's law which was named
after jordan who i referred to earlier
that law is a state law it's the first
in california to contend with media
inspired violence
so mark
give me the floor
thank you very much
as the councilman said my name is mark
berkman i am the executive director of
the organization for social media safety
i'd just like to take a moment to
acknowledge some of our supporters and
board members who are here with us today
and especially thank the city council
and councilmember blumenfield for
recognizing us and for focusing
attention on the dire need to finally
make social media safe
unfortunately the organization for
social media safety arose under tragic
circumstances
around two years ago as the council
member said
then fourteen-year-old jordan pisner
who again is here with us today
was standing with friends outside a
local fast food restaurant
when another team that he did not know
suddenly and viciously attacked him
while jordan was being attacked and then
while he lay helpless on the ground
witnesses and friends of the perpetrator
just stood there
took video and uploaded it to social
media
where it quickly and sadly went viral
having now been viewed by hundreds of
thousands
fortunately for us soon thereafter
jordan and his father ed resolved to
ensure that no other family had to
endorse such a horrific ordeal
that is when i met edin jordan heard
their story and decided to help
working together we developed and then
passed the nation's first state law
called jordan's law to deter social
media motivated violence
or violence committed for the purpose of
filming and distributing on social media
just to gain internet notoriety
while we were advocating for jordan's
law we became painfully aware of the
rapidly growing list of social media
related threats and dangers
including cyber bullying human
trafficking hate speech and propaganda
to sadly name just a few
that is why we founded the organization
for social media safety the nation's
first consumer protection organization
truly focused on social media where we
take comprehensive action to protect us
all from these serious and even
existential threats
we look forward to working with the los
angeles city council to make social
media safe for everyone in los angeles
and around the world thank you all very
much
thank you thank you so much thank you
mark um
our second final speaker is beverly
antago
beverly is a member of the student
advisory council for the organization
as well as the student government
president at california state university
northridge at csun
the student government represents
approximately 35 000 students from
around los angeles from around the los
angeles area
and of course they advocate on their
behalf
and she has a lot to say on this issue
so beverly
welcome
thank you
in this day and age many of us use
technology as a medium
for communicating with one another
whether that be through email video
conferencing or social media the value
of face-to-face interaction has lessened
as a user myself social media is a
platform that allows you to not only
elevate yourself but to also network
with people that you otherwise may not
have without the platform
i joined the organization for social
media safeties college advisory council
not to tell you all to delete your
social media accounts but rather i'm
here to inform you of the importance of
being aware of who you are communicating
with and who you're sharing information
with
it is imperative that we all educate
ourselves on the parameters of our media
accounts whether that be through our
account preferences or privacy settings
it is important to know where your
information is going and whom it is
reaching
you may be reaching the company of your
dreams but she may be reaching somebody
with ill intent
art historian michael kittson once
stated awareness is a key ingredient in
success
if you have it teach it if you lack it
seek it as the associated students
president at cal state university
northridge i encourage you all to
prosper on your various platforms
whether that be through instagram or
linkedin but make an effort to be
cognizant of what you're saying online
and who you're saying it to
thank you thank you
thank you beverly
um and to help us usher in uh social
media safety day i'm introducing two
motions today that are inspired uh by
this day that contend with media
violence i'm sorry media violence and
cyber crimes the first motion will help
advance the efforts to expand cyber
literacy
to millions by funding a successful
pilot program instituted by lapd's cyber
crimes unit
been working with them and they're
really excited about doing this
the second motion will allow more people
to make private online police reports
this will link the myla 311 and the lapd
online reporting tool it also will
expand the number of crimes which can be
reported online to include
prominent cyber crimes and a tip line
for cyber crime
red flags
these two motions will serve as the
backbone in the effort to empower every
single community member to to counter
cyber crimes
now i'd like to uh present you all with
a social media safety day
uh
certificate that's been signed by every
member of the city council here
because we're all excited to to bring
forward the very first and hopefully
annual social media safety day let's
give them all a big round of applause
hey mr blumenfield
before you leave uh and bets maybe we
can hold for a minute on the photo i'd
like to recognize mr marquis harristos
thank you so much
cher i just wanted to rise and thank you
mr blumenfeld and the organizations and
individuals that are represented with
you uh today this is uh one of those
things that doesn't get nearly as much
attention as it deserves uh it can both
um
be the you can have a cyber crime that
is isolated but what but what
social media can do with violence and
crime is what it does with everything
else it can make it spread
so you will remember three years ago in
my district we had an outbreak of of
homicides that was driven mostly by
social media and you joined uh with a
number of us to ask the social media
companies hey stop profiting
from this stop profiting from pictures
of people getting shot or fights in the
street and so on and so forth so i
wanted to make sure i stood up and on
behalf of the folks of the 8th district
and around the city thank you for this
presentation and thank you all for your
work
betsy the floor is yours
give the floor to the photographer
just follow me back this way
uh let's uh city attorney uh i've been
informed that item 14
we should be able to take up can you
speak to that briefly
it's the closed session item i believe
the hearing was already
held or madame clerk maybe you could
speak to it
yes mr president on item 14 in the case
entitled rj a minor at all versus the
city of los angeles at all there is a
recommendation to expend up to 500
thousand dollars in settlement okay
let's prepare to vote on that item
please open the roll
close the roll tab you laid the vote
twelve eyes one no all right
that brings us where madam clerk
that takes counsel to item 13.
okay um
sergeants
we're going to
be going in a closed session
if you could clear the chambers
[Music]
do
we're trying to make it one call to city
hall for everything and so we've been in
collaboration with our i.t department
and with the mayor's office and just
trying to get as much information as we
can so that we can help people faster
better and more efficiently and solve
problems prior to to these this
collaboration
we were answering all of our calls and
they were getting bogged down so we just
had to sort of figure out what we you
know how can we do this and we did a lot
of scripting to help the 311 operators
know how to answer so that we could
divert just the emergency calls to the
shelter and that way we can handle the
emergencies much quicker and much more
efficiently
[Music]
so
it's such an interesting global
phenomenon and
oftentimes the art world is
kind of missing a fun
party vibe
what i'm trying to do here is just
really trying to understand what's
happening right now in korea whenever i
go back to seoul all i see is k-pop
everywhere really and k-pop is
rising as like a huge part of the modern
culture of south korea
[Music]
well today is a special art walk because
it is uh twofold it is one the kwanzaa
days
today is nia which means purpose it's
also the art walk sunday
[Music]
this neighborhood in particular lemur
park is like the mecca of the
african-american cultural center where a
lot of the shops are here the vendors
come here the food that we like and the
drumming and the dancing
the purpose of getting together is
just focus clarity and getting and
community family fellowship
with not only our culture but with
everybody's culture
[Music]
having the foresight to plan for my
business to plan for my future to plan
for my family provides a peace of mind
having the foresight to sign up for
alert l.a county gives me that peace of
mind when an incident happens close to
my home or near my park alert la county
is a free automated system which sends
out information about emergency events
via telephone text and email events may
include disasters evacuations and safety
notices register at alert.la
alert.lacounty.gov alert la county
knowing when you need it most
three
two
one
please join me in welcoming to our
celebration today kobe bryant
congrats on welcoming 50 million
visitors this right here is a
championship moment los angeles is a
place that draws people here we're
magnetic come to l.a try one of our
famous tacos grab a dodger dog
experience the awe and the wonder
standing beneath a space shuttle that's
actually gone into the heavens and
returned before going over to see
griffith observatory to watch the most
beautiful sunset on the face of the
earth as the city lights come up like a
bed of jewels at night well if you know
the los angeles is one of the most
instagrammable cities in the world the
hashtag los angeles averages nearly 40
000 new photos each and every day
[Music]
we are known together as the place that
is an epicenter of seismic risk but we
hope today this is another big step
forward to being the epicenter of
seismic preparedness understanding the
shake alert system and how it could be
useful for angelino's and then actually
building the app with att and coal works
to be able to create something that
anybody can download that will give them
precious seconds of warning before the
earthquake occurs we were able to get it
down to an average of 1.88 seconds of
latency from the time we first
understand that an earthquake is
happening to the time it's delivered on
somebody's cell phone
when you receive an alert it will look
and sound like this
it's not a matter of if it's going to
happen but when and so this app
hopefully is going to put it in people's
minds that we need to prepare now we
have a technology that can notify us
when this earthquake is coming what are
the actions that i will take
so
[Music]
one thing i believe in is to keep our
neighborhoods clean and looking better
because when your neighborhoods look
better and you walk down the sidewalk
and it's a more pleasant experience
there's actually a physiological and a
spiritual component to that we really
need to care for our public rights of
way because these are our collective
cathedrals
[Music]
we're doing some really great things in
the echo park community
today next month we're here in echo park
we're doing cleanups we're picking up
bulky items we're painting up graffiti
and we're knocking on doors informing
constituents of the resources from the
city that are available to them free and
then i get to meet more people that i
represent they don't have any help here
you do now come on you do now
thank you
[Music]
i'd like to begin this eventful day
by welcoming all of you to brantford
today we celebrate the grand opening of
our new and innovative playground
this is where learning imagination
and friendships will flourish
this is the uh reopening of our
playground area here at brownford park
this has been almost five years in the
making
this all came about because of neighbors
across the street who said that this
park needed a little bit more attention
if it wasn't for them and this amazing
community all around this area
some of this would not be possible so
thanks to them and thanks to reckon
parks for finding the money and making
this a dream come true
we're here at dodgers
[Music]
it's gonna be a great year
it's awesome to see
that as much as we give and we love the
dodgers they give back so i was standing
over there and justin turner came up and
i touched my hand and i'm never washing
his hand because justin turner touched
it
[Music]
okay
today is the museum's oshogansu program
it's
celebrating the new year and this is the
year of the board
[Music]
again
hey dad
dad
there are other ways of saving money and
energy around your house did you know
that ladwp is now offering cash rebates
for you to retrofit your home to be more
energy and water efficient it's good for
california and it's good for dad
let's make california a better place to
live starting with our homes to get your
rebates go to www.ladwp.com
[Music]
read while you wait is a community-based
literacy program that provides access to
quality children's books for customers
who are waiting for service i like the
fact that i can read when i'm waiting to
get my hair cut and that i'm not just
sitting here bored it's really nice to
read while i wait for my brother to
finish his hair this program is an
opportunity for children to get exposed
to a whole new world through reading
it allows them to help reach their full
potential
regardless of what aspect in life they
want to go to if it's engineering the
doctors lawyers reading is the primary
basis to whatever the library wants to
create positive associations with
reading and this is a fun way for us to
provide great access to books to them in
a non-academic setting
[Music]
good morning i am proud to be here on
the world famous the largest urban park
in the nation griffith park to host the
fifth annual griffith park run
[Music]
i had a fantastic day for the 5k
and what a beautiful day with so many
thousands of people running
i think it's bigger this year actually
more people the weather is a little bit
warmer than usual so it's all good
[Music]
we have theater dance music film
festivals
all kinds of performance art we have
classes seven days a week and theater
upstairs this is a solar-powered space
we produce about a third of our power on
the roof
and we buy only green power from dwp
the electrolyzer is a wonderful place
it's benefited so many young students
the vibe is good
[Music]
it's just overwhelming
to see all this history on the wall and
and to know that some of my peers are
still here to celebrate this
i think it's important to really
recognize and to honor
all of the people who started out in a
period when there really wasn't much
available in terms of film
my family is here my kids my
grandchildren and for them to really see
their grandmother you know and to see
this happening just means the world to
me
[Music]
the information technology agency is
here at this emergency exercise because
there are two things happening in an
emergency simulation today one is
there's a cyber attack which means that
people are attacking the systems that
manage the city of los angeles and
number two is that there are simulated
explosions happening across some of our
transit systems so information
technology plays a key role in how
people normally communicate during
emergency so we are simulating that
those systems are down today if we had a
real disaster the idea that you know
your fellow responder is big because now
you've had a chance to practice together
play together and you'll work better
together ultimately we have people that
are ready and trained to act and
keep people safe and keep them informed
how to help me
[Music]
can you tell me a part of
african-american history that resonates
with you oh wow dr martin luther king jr
i mean that speech i have a dream is one
of the moments i think you know america
had to take a moment and hear his words
it was a time in which we began to
define who we were and made more steps
towards realizing the freedom that our
forefathers had fought for
i will be reciting the black statue of
liberty poem i'm taking all of my people
back home and breaking them mentally
free so no statue and a big apple can
mess with me because i'm the walking
talking breathing surviving beautiful
black statue of liberty
[Music]
okay
today's a great day here in chinatown
we're having the chinese new year
celebrating with this parade really
welcoming all of angelinos to come out
and celebrate part of our part of our
history part of our culture
[Music]
happy new
go hate year
time
[Music]
we're trying to make it one call to city
hall for everything and so we've been in
collaboration with our i.t department
and with the mayor's office and just
trying to get as much information as we
can so that we can help people faster
better more efficiently and solve
problems prior to to these this
collaboration
we were answering all of our calls and
they were getting bogged down so we just
had to sort of figure out what we you
know how can we do this and we did a lot
of scripting to help the 311 operators
know how to answer so that we could
divert just the emergency calls to the
shelter and that way we can handle the
emergencies much quicker and much more
efficiently
[Music]
foreign
it's such an interesting global
phenomenon and
oftentimes the art world is
kind of missing a fun
party vibe
what i'm trying to do here is just
really trying to understand what's
happening right now in korea whenever i
go back to seoul all i see is k-pop
everywhere really and k-pop is
rising as a huge part of the modern
culture of south korea
[Music]
well today is a special art walk because
it is uh twofold it is the one the
kwanzaa days
today is nia which means purpose it's
also the art walk sunday
[Music]
this neighborhood in particular lemur
park is like the mecca of the
african-american cultural center where a
lot of the shops are here the vendors
come here the food that we like and the
drumming and the dancing
the purpose of getting together is
just focus clarity and getting and
community family fellowship
with not only our culture but with
everybody's culture
[Music]
having the foresight to plan for my
business to plan for my future to plan
for my family provides a peace of mind
having the foresight to sign up for
alert l.a county gives me that peace of
mind when an incident happens close to
my home or near my park alert la county
is a free automated system which sends
out information about emergency events
via telephone text and email events may
include disasters evacuations and safety
notices register at
alert.lacounty.gov alert la county
knowing when you need it most
three
two one
please join me in welcoming to our
celebration today kobe bryant
congrats on welcoming 50 million
visitors this right here is a
championship moment los angeles is a
place that draws people to we're
magnetic come to l.a try one of our
famous tacos grab a dodger dog
experience the awe and the wonder
standing beneath a space shuttle that's
actually gone into the heavens and
returned before going over to see
griffith observatory to watch the most
beautiful sunset on the face of the
earth as the city lights come up like a
bed of jewels at night well if you know
the los angeles is one of the most
instagrammable cities in the world the
hashtag los angeles averages nearly 40
000 new photos each and every day
[Music]
so
we have are known together as the place
that is an epicenter of seismic risk but
we hope today this is another big step
forward to being the epicenter of
seismic preparedness understanding the
shake alert system and how it could be
useful for angelino's and then actually
building the app with a t and call works
to be able to create something that
anybody can download that will give them
precious seconds of warning before the
earthquake occurs we were able to get it
down to an average of 1.88 seconds of
latency from the time we first
understand that an earthquake is
happening to the time it's delivered on
somebody's cell phone
when you receive an alert it will look
and sound like this
[Music]
it's not a matter of if it's going to
happen but when and so this app
hopefully is going to put it in people's
minds that we need to prepare now we
have a technology that can notify us
when this earthquake is coming what are
the actions that i will take
so
[Music]
one thing i believe in is to keep our
neighborhoods clean and looking better
because when your neighborhoods look
better and you walk down the sidewalk
and it's a more pleasant experience
there's actually a physiological and a
spiritual component to that we really
need to care for our public rights of
way because these are our collective
cathedrals
[Music]
we're doing some really great things in
the echo park community
today next month we're here in echo park
we're doing cleanups we're picking up
bulky items we're painting out graffiti
and we're knocking on doors informing
constituents of the resources from the
city that are available to them free and
then i get to meet more people that i
represent they don't have any help here
you do now come on you do now
thank you
[Music]
i'd like to begin this eventful day
by welcoming all of you to brantford
today we celebrate the grand opening of
our new and innovative playground
this is where learning imagination
and friendships will flourish
this is the reopening of our playground
area here at brownford park this has
been almost five years in the making
this all came about because of neighbors
across the street who said that this
park needed a little bit more attention
if it wasn't for them and this amazing
community all around this area
some of this would not be possible so
thanks to them and thanks to reckon
parks are finding the money and making
this a dream come true
we're here at dodgers fan fest
[Music]
it's gonna be a great year for dodgers
it's awesome to see that as much as we
give and we love the dodgers they give
back so i was standing over there and
justin turner came up and i touched my
hand and i'm never washing his hand
because justin turner touched it
[Music]
you
today is the museum's oshogansu program
it's
celebrating the new year and this is the
year of the board
[Music]
so
not it again
hey dad
dad
there are other ways of saving money and
energy around your house did you know
that ladwp is now offering cash rebates
for you to retrofit your home to be more
energy and water efficient it's good for
california and it's good for dad
let's make california a better place to
live starting with our homes to get your
rebates go to www.ladwp.com
[Music]
read while you wait is a community-based
literacy program that provides access to
quality children's books for customers
who are waiting for service i like the
fact that i can read when i'm waiting to
get my hair cut and that i'm not just
sitting here bored it's really nice to
read while i wait for my brother to
finish his hair this program is an
opportunity for children to get exposed
to a whole new world through reading
it allows them to help reach their full
potential
regardless of what aspect and life they
want to go to if it's engineering the
doctors lawyers reading is the primary
basis to whatever the library wants to
create positive associations with
reading and this is a fun way for us to
provide great access to books to them in
a non-academic setting
[Music]
good morning i am proud to be here on
the world famous the largest urban park
in the nation griffith park to host the
fifth annual griffith park run
who came here
today had a great day i had a fantastic
day for the 5k
and what a beautiful day with so many
thousands of people running
everything's bigger this year actually
more people the weather is nice a little
bit warmer than usual so it's all good
[Music]
we have theater dance music film
festivals
all kinds of performance art we have
classes seven days a week and theater
upstairs this is a solar-powered space
we produce about a third of our power on
the roof
and we buy only green power from dwp
the electrolyzer is a wonderful place
it's benefited so many young students
the vibe is good
[Music]
it's just overwhelming
to see all this history on the wall and
and to know that some of my peers are
still here to celebrate this
i think it's important to really
recognize and to honor
all of the people who started out in a
period when there really wasn't much
available in terms of film
my family is here my kids my
grandchildren and for them to really see
their grandmother you know and to see
this happening just means the world to
me
[Music]
the information technology agency is
here at this emergency exercise because
there are two things happening in an
emergency simulation today one is
there's a cyber attack which means that
people are attacking the systems that
manage the city of los angeles and
number two is that there are simulated
explosions happening across some of our
transit systems so information
technology plays a key role in how
people normally communicate during
emergency so we are simulating that
those systems are down today if we had a
real disaster the idea that you know
your fellow responder is big because now
you've had a chance to practice together
play together and you'll work better
together ultimately we have people that
are ready and trained to act and
keep people safe and keep them informed
[Music]
can you tell me a part of
african-american history that resonates
with you oh wow dr martin luther king jr
i mean that speech i have a dream is one
of the moments i think you know america
had to take a moment and hear his words
it was a time in which we began to
define who we were and made more steps
towards realizing the freedom that our
forefathers had fought for
i will be reciting the black statue of
liberty poem i'm taking all of my people
back home and breaking them mentally
free so no statue and a big apple can
mess with me cause i'm the walking
talking breathing surviving beautiful
black statue of liberty
[Music]
okay
today's a great day here in chinatown
we're having the chinese new year
celebrating with this parade really
welcoming all of angelinos to come out
and celebrate part of our part of our
history part of our culture
[Music]
happy new year
go ahead
[Music]
we're trying to make it one call to city
hall for everything and so we've been in
collaboration with our i.t department
and with the mayor's office and just
trying to get as much information as we
can so that we can help people faster
better and more efficiently and solve
problems prior to to these this
collaboration
we were answering all of our calls and
they were getting bogged down so we just
had to sort of figure out what we you
know how could we do this and we did a
lot of scripting to help the 311
operators know how to answer so that we
could divert just the emergency calls to
the shelter and that way we can handle
the emergencies much quicker and much
more efficiently
[Music]
so
it's such an interesting global
phenomenon and oftentimes the art world
is
kind of missing a fun
party vibe
what i'm trying to do here is just
really trying to understand what's
happening right now in korea whenever i
go back to seoul all i see is k-pop
everywhere really and k-pop is
rising as like a huge part of the modern
culture of south korea
[Music]
well today is a special art walk because
it is uh twofold it is the one the
kwanzaa days uh today is nia which means
purpose it's also the art walk sunday
[Music]
this neighborhood in particular lemur
park is like the mecca of the
african-american cultural center where a
lot of the shops are here the vendors
come here the food that we like and the
drumming and the dancing
the purpose of getting together is
just focus clarity and getting and
community family fellowship
with not only our culture but with
everybody's culture
[Music]
having the foresight to plan for my
business to plan for my future to plan
for my family provides a peace of mind
having the foresight to sign up for
alert l.a county gives me that peace of
mind when an incident happens close to
my home or near my park alert la county
is a free automated system which sends
out information about emergency events
via telephone text and email events may
include disasters evacuations and safety
notices register at
alert.lacounty.gov alert la county
knowing when you need it most
[Music]
three
two
one
please join me in welcoming to our
celebration today kobe bryant
congrats on welcoming 50 million
visitors this right here is a
championship moment los angeles is a
place that draws people here we're
magnetic come to l.a try one of our
famous tacos grab a dodger dog
experience the awe and the wonder
standing beneath a space shuttle that's
actually gone into the heavens and
returned before going over to see
griffith observatory to watch the most
beautiful sunset on the face of the
earth as the city lights come up like a
bed of jewels at night well if you know
the los angeles is one of the most
instagrammable cities in the world the
hashtag los angeles averages nearly 40
000 new photos each and every day
[Music]
we have are known together as the place
that is an epicenter of seismic risk but
we hope today this is another big step
forward to being the epicenter of
seismic preparedness understanding the
shake alert system and how it could be
useful for angelino's and then actually
building the app with att and coal works
to be able to create something that
anybody can download that will give them
precious seconds of warning before the
earthquake occurs we were able to get it
down to an average of 1.88 seconds of
latency from the time we first
understand that an earthquake is
happening to the time it's delivered on
somebody's cell phone
when you receive an alert it will look
and sound like this
[Music]
it's not a matter of if it's going to
happen but when and so this app
hopefully is going to put it in people's
minds that we need to prepare now we
have a technology that can notify us
when this earthquake is coming what are
the actions that i will take
[Music]
one thing i believe in is to keep our
neighborhoods clean and looking better
because when your neighborhoods look
better and you walk down the sidewalk
and it's a more pleasant experience
there's actually a physiological and a
spiritual component to that we really
need to care for our public rights of
way because these are our collective
cathedrals
[Music]
we're doing some really great things in
the echo park community
today next month we're here in echo park
we're doing cleanups we're picking up
bulky items we're painting out graffiti
and we're knocking on doors informing
constituents of the resources from the
city that are available to them free and
then i get to meet more people that i
represent they don't have any help here
you do now come on you do now
thank you
[Music]
so
do
[Music]
i'd like to begin this eventful day
by welcoming all of you to brantford
we celebrate the grand opening of our
new and innovative playground
this is where learning imagination
and friendships will flourish this is
the reopening of our playground area
here at brownford park
this has been almost five years in the
maki
this all came about because of neighbors
across the street who said that this
park needed a little bit more attention
if it wasn't for them
and it's amazing community all around
this area some of this would not be
possible so thanks to them and thanks to
reckon parks for finding the money and
making this a dream come true
we're here at dodgers fan fest
[Music]
it's awesome to see
that as much as we give and we love the
dodgers they give back so i was standing
over there and justin turner came up and
i touched my hand and i'm never washing
his hand because justin turner touched
it
[Music]
oh
today is the museum's oshogansu program
it's celebrating the new year and this
is the year of the board
[Music]
i feel
again
hey dad
dad
there are other ways of saving money and
energy around your house did you know
that ladwp is now offering cash rebates
for you to retrofit your home to be more
energy and water efficient it's good for
california and it's good for dad let's
make california a better place to live
starting with our homes to get your
rebates go to www.ladwp.com
[Music]
read while you wait is a community-based
literacy
program that provides access to quality
children's books for customers who are
waiting for service i like the fact that
i can read when i'm waiting to get my
hair cut and that i'm not just sitting
here bored it's really nice to read
while i wait for my brother to finish
his hair this program is an opportunity
for children to get exposed to a whole
new world through reading
it allows them to help reach their full
potential uh regardless of what aspect
in life they want to go to if it's
engineering the doctors lawyers reading
is the primary basis to whatever the
library wants to create positive
associations with reading and this is a
fun way for us to provide great access
to books to them in a non-academic
setting
[Music]
good morning i am proud to be here on
the world famous the largest urban park
in the nation griffith park to host the
fifth annual griffith park run
i had a fantastic day for the 5k
and what a beautiful day with so many
thousands of people running
everything's bigger this year actually
more people the weather is nice a little
bit warmer than usual so it's all good
[Music]
we have theater dance music film
festivals
all kinds of performance art we have
classes seven days a week and theater
upstairs this is a solar powered space
we produce about a third of our power on
the roof
and we buy only green power from dwp
the electrolyze is a wonderful place
it's benefited so many young students
the vibe is good
[Music]
it's just overwhelming
to see all this history on the wall and
and to know that some of my peers are
still here to celebrate this
i think it's important to really
recognize and to honor
all of the people who started out in a
period when there really wasn't much
available in terms of film
my family is here my kids my
grandchildren and for them to really see
their grandmother you know and to see
this happening just means the world to
me
[Music]
the information technology agency is
here at this emergency exercise because
there are two things happening in an
emergency simulation today one is
there's a cyber attack which means that
people are attacking the systems that
manage the city of los angeles and
number two is that there are simulated
explosions happening across some of our
transit systems so information
technology plays a key role in how
people normally communicate during
emergency so we are simulating that
those systems are down today if we had a
real disaster the idea that you know
your fellow responder is big because now
you've had a chance to practice together
play together and you'll work better
together ultimately we have people that
are ready and trained to act and
keep people safe and keep them informed
you
[Music]
can you tell me a part of
african-american history that resonates
with you oh wow dr martin luther king jr
i mean that speech i have a dream is one
of the moments i think you know america
had to take a moment and hear his words
it was a time in which we began to
define who we were and made more steps
towards realizing the freedom that our
forefathers had fought for
i will be reciting the black statue of
liberty poem i'm taking all of my people
back home and breaking them mentally
free so no statue and a big apple can
mess with me cause i'm the walking
talking breathing surviving beautiful
black statue of liberty
[Music]
okay
today's a great day here in chinatown
we're having the chinese new year
celebrating with this parade really
welcoming all of angelinos to come out
and celebrate part of our part of our
history part of our culture
happy new year
go ahead
[Music]
we're trying to make it one call to city
hall for everything and so we've been in
collaboration with our i.t department
and with the mayor's office and just
trying to get as much information as we
can so that we can help people faster
better more efficiently and solve
problems prior to
these this collaboration uh we were
answering all of our calls and they were
getting bogged down so we just had to
sort of figure out what we you know how
can we do this and we did a lot of
scripting to help the 311 operators know
how to answer so that we could divert
just the emergency calls to the shelter
and that way we can handle the
emergencies much quicker and much more
efficiently
[Music]
bye
so
[Music]
it's such an interesting global
phenomenon and
oftentimes the art world is
kind of missing a fun
party vibe
what i'm trying to do here is just
really trying to understand what's
happening right now in korea whenever i
go back to seoul all i see is k-pop
everywhere really and k-pop is
rising as like a huge part of the modern
culture of south korea
[Music]
well today is a special art walk because
it is
twofold it is the one the kwanzaa days
today is mia which means purpose it's
also the art walk sunday
[Music]
this neighborhood in particular lemur
park is like the mecca of the
african-american cultural center where a
lot of the shops are here the vendors
come here the food that we like and the
drumming and the dancing
the purpose of getting together is
just focus clarity and getting and
community family fellowship
with not only our culture but with
everybody's culture
[Music]
having the foresight to plan for my
business to plan for my future to plan
for my family provides a peace of mind
having the foresight to sign up for
alert l.a county gives me that peace of
mind when an incident happens close to
my home or near my park alert la county
is a free automated system which sends
out information about emergency events
via telephone text and email events may
include disasters evacuations and safety
notices register at
alert.lacounty.gov alert la county
knowing when you need it most
[Music]
three
two one
[Music]
please join me in welcoming to our
celebration today kobe bryant
congrats on welcoming 50 million
visitors this right here is a
championship moment los angeles is a
place that draws people here we're
magnetic come to la try one of our
famous tacos grab a dodger dog
experience the awe and the wonder
standing beneath a space shuttle that's
actually gone into the heavens and
returned before going over to see
griffith observatory to watch the most
beautiful sunset on the face of the
earth as the city lights come up like a
bed of jewels at night well if you know
the los angeles is one of the most
instagrammable cities in the world the
hashtag los angeles averages nearly 40
000 new photos each and every day
[Music]
we are known together as the place that
is an epicenter of seismic risk but we
hope today this is another big step
forward to being the epicenter of
seismic preparedness understanding the
shake alert system and how it could be
useful for angelino's and then actually
building the app with att and coleworks
to be able to create something that
anybody can download that will give them
precious seconds of warning before the
earthquake occurs we were able to get it
down to an average of 1.88 seconds of
latency from the time we first
understand that an earthquake is
happening to the time it's delivered on
somebody's cell phone
when you receive an alert it will look
and sound like this
[Music]
it's not a matter of if it's going to
happen but when and so this app
hopefully is going to put it in people's
minds that we need to prepare now we
have a technology that can notify us
when this earthquake is coming what are
the actions that i will take
[Music]
one thing i believe in is to keep our
neighborhoods clean and looking better
because when your neighborhoods look
better and you walk down the sidewalk
and it's a more pleasant experience
there's actually a physiological and a
spiritual component to that we really
need to care for our public rights of
way because these are our collective
cathedrals
[Music]
we're doing some really great things in
the echo park community
today next month we're here in echo park
we're doing cleanups we're picking up
bulky items we're painting out graffiti
and we're knocking on doors informing
constituents of the resources from the
city that are available to them free and
then i get to meet more people that i
represent and we don't have any help
here you do now come on you do now
thank you
[Music]
okay let us now
call us into open session
uh what's before us now is item 13
yes item 13. the recommendation is for
council to approve a settlement with the
recycle la service providers to resolve
a contract dispute regarding the
application of certain fees or charges
for extra service
this settlement approval authorizes a
contract amendment and substantial
conformity with the settlement to be
transmitted to the awarding authority
for its consideration as well as to
counsel for its approval
thank you so with that let us open the
role
close the roll tabulate the vote 13 eyes
one no
fantastic next item
next item item seven
seven a an amending motion has been
posted and circulated for council's
consideration
the first vote let us reconsider then
item seven
open the vote
close the roll tabulate the vote
fourteen eyes
with that uh let's now
item number seven is before us as
amended
let us now open the roll
close the roll
tabulate the vote 14 eyes
thank you next item
and that takes counsel
to motions that they have for posting
and approval
they are posted and referred
and that clears the desk thank you any
announcements colleagues
mr marquis harris dawson thank you so
much mr chair uh and colleagues um
i uh want to for the good of the record
just present a general public comment
that in the last 72 hours uh elected
officials in our city and our state have
done a lot to move the ball towards
justice and i just wanted to mark it for
the record
this city council
voted to call out those who decide to
enter into friendships with the greatest
purveyor of bad gun policy in the
country we decided that in los angeles
we can still
dress nice without refer without relying
on fur
and the wanting killing of animals
our mayor and along with several of our
colleagues decided to shut down a
gas-powered plant
on the coast
in the county just up the hill
they decided against a new prison in
lancaster and to turn
men's central jail into what it should
have been for many years and that is a
mental health treatment facility and i
just think that's a big deal in 72 hours
and and it ought to be recognized uh
here in the city of los angeles
thank you thank you any other
announcements colleagues
see none
adjourning motions
mr wizard
i'll rise for adjourning emotions
thank you mr president and colleagues i
wish to adjourn in memory of henry
ronquillo the legendary former principal
of roosevelt high school and beloved
member of the roughrider family
he transformed the lives of so many
through his dedication as a teacher
principal and deeply rooted community
member henry ronquillo was born on march
11 1936 in el paso texas and was the
youngest of six children to parents
manuel and elisa roquillo in 1942 the
family moved to los angeles and lived in
the newly opened peaker gardens housing
project in bow heights where henry
attended 2nd street elementary holland
back middle school and graduated from
roosevelt high school in 1954.
after playing basketball for roosevelt
high school in east los angeles college
he was awarded a full athletic
basketball scholarship by the university
of oregon where he graduated from from
in 1959 with a bachelor of science from
there he set off to what would become a
lifeline of dedication to uplifting our
youth especially in the neighborhood
that had shaped him so much and that is
bowl heights
he was hired as a teacher at roosevelt
high school and stevenson middle school
where he worked during the 1960s and 70s
he continued to be an inspiration to his
students by obtaining a master's degree
from claremont graduate university in
1975.
he climbed the educational leadership
ladder and served as an assistant
principal at garfield high school and
principal at adams middle school before
he becoming principal at his alma mater
roosevelt high school henry ronchillo
served with distinction as a principal
of roosevelt high school from 1983 to
2002 for a record 20 years that remains
unmatched in the history of the school
mr ronquillo also became a member of the
founding group of alumni who created the
roosevelt alumni association
ever the socially conscious principle in
a more more memorable occasion to honor
those who served in 1997 principal
ronquillo presented honorary high school
diplomas to more than 100 world war ii
veterans many of them posthumously who
left school before graduation because
they were drafted or volunteered to join
the service where they fought bravely
and honorably for our country
in another memorable and emotional
occasion mr ronker presented honorary
high school diplomas to many japanese
americans who were forced to leave
roosevelt high school in bowl heights
and sent to internment camps during
world war ii
it is important to note that under his
tenure about 80 teachers who were
roosevelt alumni were hired to serve and
give back to the same community they had
grown up in he understood that rough
rider pride is a unifying thread that
weaves throughout the school and
community uniting past and present and
making roosevelt the unique place that
it is
in 2002 mr rookie retired after 43 years
in the los angeles unified school
district a career that spanned six
decades his dedication to the community
was unwavering and in post retirement he
continued to serve as board member for
the roosevelt alumni foundation
this past year the associated
administrators of los angeles awarded a
roosevelt student with the first ever
henry ronquillo honorary scholarship at
a ceremony where mr unkill was
recognized for his notable career the
rough rider family was deeply saddened
by the passing of mr ronquillo but his
legacy carried on through each and every
one of the lives he touched
a huge supporter of the school's
athletic programs he was in many ways
the greatest to roosevelt's many
boosters for this and many more reasons
mr will be deeply missed services will
be held for him on thursday february
21st at 11 a.m in
area community church located at 8 100
kalima road in whittier our most sincere
and deepest condolences to his family
and friends may he rest in peace
thank you mr wizard and the others
i have one members i'd like to adjourn
in memory of gary mattingly appointed as
the general manager of the department of
el uh fire and police pensions on june 6
until he retired on december 4th 2004
even after retirement he continued to
serve as interim general manager until
june 2005. mr mattingly was one of the
longest servant general managers at the
la
fire and police pensions he served for
37 years for the city he was appointed
when he was appointed the fund was
valued at nearly 1.5 billion dollars and
grew to 12.3 billion when he left city
service in 2005. after retirement he
went on to serve the credit union board
of los angeles city employees retirement
system board in addition to being
committed to the welfare community mr
mattingly enjoyed traveling and spending
time with his family and friends
he raised three children with his wife
paula petrotta our hearts go out to the
entire madeline family may he rest in
peace
thank you any others seeing none
we are now adjourned go forth and serve
the people this great city thank you
[Music]